<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thunder Op-Ed</title>
    <description>Welcome to Thunder Op-Ed! Come back often or follow us on twitter  for content, thoughts, and ramblings on your Oklahoma City Thunder. This site is independent of the OKC Thunder organization and all views expressed are that of the author.
</description>
    <link>http://thunderoped.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thunderoped.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 14:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 14:25:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coming This Week (3/19 - 3/26)</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;games&quot;&gt;Games&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;golden-state-warriors-at-oklahoma-city-thunder&quot;&gt;Golden State Warriors at Oklahoma City Thunder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gametime: Monday, March 20, 2017, 7:00PM CST (TNT only)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be the fourth, and final, rematch of the 2016 Western Conference Finals. The Warriors have won the previous three installments. The first game between these two teams was a blowout, with the Warriors winning 122-96. The second game saw the Warriors win 121-100. The third matchup was Kevin Durant’s return to Oklahoma City for his first game as a visitor in the Cheseapeake Arena. This was the closest of the games so far this season, with Golden State still managing to come away with a 130-114 win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is good news for the Thunder, however. Kevin Durant will be missing this game as he recovers from a knee injury. In 3 games against his former team, Durant averaged 37.7 ppg, 9.3 rpg, and 2.7 apg. He managed these numbers on 65.6% shooting from the floor, with a devastating 62.5% from three-point range. The Thunder will rejoice in not having to game plan for Durant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;philadelphia-76ers-at-oklahoma-city-thunder&quot;&gt;Philadelphia 76ers at Oklahoma City Thunder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gametime: Wednesday, March 22, 2017, 7:00PM CST (FSOK)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game will see Jerami Grant playing against his former team. The 76ers are a young team in the long process of a rebuild. The franchise has been in rebuild mode for several years now. This year they seem to have put together a few nice runs and have shown some improvement. The team is really young and has a few good young players. Joel Embiid was a strong front runner for rookie of the year until his injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder are in a tight race with the Utah Jazz for the division championship. If they want to catch the Jazz they have to take advantage of winnable games. This surely is one. However, being placed in between two western conference contenders this could be a bit of a trap game. The Thunder will need to come out and take care of business early to put Philadelphia out of the game early on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-thunder-at-houston-rockets&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Thunder at Houston Rockets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gametime: Sunday, March 26, 2017, 2:30PM CST (ABC)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game will have a lot of viewers. Sunday afternoon NBA games are some of the best ways to kill a day before the real world comes back around. This particular game will feature the two leading MVP candidates and a potential first round playoffs preview. James Harden, previously the Oklahoma City 6th man, is having by far his best season as a professional nearly averaging a triple double and has the Houston Rockets playing their best basketball in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Houston is 2-1 versus the Thunder this season. The three games these teams have already played this season have been decided by a combined 7 points. This should be another fun game between the two teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever and always, Thunder up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/03-19-2017/Weekly-Preview/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/03-19-2017/Weekly-Preview/</guid>
        
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Week In Review (11/9-11/16)</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;games&quot;&gt;Games&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;los-angeles-clippers-110--108-oklahoma-city-thunder&quot;&gt;Los Angeles Clippers 110 – 108 Oklahoma City Thunder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Clippers came out and played a better game offensively than they did just last week against the Oklahoma City Thunder. The difference seems to have been Blake Griffin’s performance. In the first game against the Clippers, the Thunder held him to just 14 points on 7-of-21 shooting. However, he managed 25 points on an efficient 10-of-20 shooting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russell Westbrook led the Thunder in scoring again this game dropping 29 points. He shot poorly however making just 9 of 25 shots. He did finish with 15 rebounds, and 9 assists though. He limited himself to just 4 turnovers as well. The end of the game was a sad one for Thunder fans. With just over 11 seconds left in the game, the Thunder had the ball on the baseline. Westbrook drove up the court and pulled up for a challenged three from deep. It was not a great shot. However, the rest of the team on the floor at the time gave him no movement to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bright spot out of this game is that the scoring was more spread out. Four players other than Westbrook scored in double digits. Domas Sabonis scored 12 points on 4-of-5 shooting – all of which came from behind the three point line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Victor Oladipo finished with 18 points, albeit on 6-of-18 shooting from the floor. He did manage to hit half (4) of this three point attempts (8). This is the Oladipo Thunder fans were expecting when he was traded to OKC on draft night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andre Roberson poured in another 13 points making half of his shots from the floor, including 3 three-point attempts. Roberson also secured 9 rebounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enes Kanter rounded out the double-digit scoring club with 13 points on 6-of-11 shooting. He also grabbed 11 rebounds for his fourth double-double of the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an odd twist of fate, all Thunder starters ended with a negative plus/minus score, while all bench players (except Nick Collison) ended with a positive plus/minus score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder also seemed to have found some rhythm from deep. The team went 16-28 from beyond the arc for a 57.1% conversion rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;orlando-magic-119--117-oklahoma-city-thunder&quot;&gt;Orlando Magic 119 – 117 Oklahoma City Thunder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serge Ibaka lit up his former team in his first return trip to Oklahoma City. Ibaka still holds a special place in Thunder hearts as he was the last of the original star Thunder players to leave town. He was traded on draft night to the Orlando Magic in exchange for Victor Oladipo, Ersan Ilyasova, and the rights to Domas Sabonis. Ilyasova has since been traded to Philadelphia, while Victor Oladipo and Domas Sabonis remain fixtures in the Thunder starting five.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ibaka scored a new career high of 31 points on an incredible 13-of-19 shooting. He even made both of his three-point attempts. He also had the game winning shot that stole the breath of his former hometown crowd. With just a few seconds remaining in the game the Magic ran a play designed to get Ibaka open and they ran it to perfection. Ibaka got the ball going away from the basket and hit a challenged jump shot over former paint-protecting buddy Steven Adams to put the Magic on top with just 0.4 seconds left in the game. The Thunder called a timeout and advanced the ball to half-court where Billy Donovan drew up a lob play for Russell Westbrook. The pass was a little high and the timing did not work out and the Thunder lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westbrook did have a great game though. He scored 41 points on an efficient 14-of-21 shooting, though he missed his three attempts from long distance. He also created a lot of opportunities for his teammates finishing with 16 assists and even pulled down 12 rebounds. This was his third triple-double of the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steven Adams scored 13 points and pulled down 10 rebounds for his third triple-double of the season. Victor Oladipo and Andre Roberson turned in solid performances as well. Oladipo finished with 12 points on 6-of-9 shooting. Roberson had his second game in a row of scoring in double digits. He finished with 13 points on 6-of-11 shooting. He also blocked 4 shots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enes Kanter nearly had another double-double. In 24 minutes off the bench, he scored 16 points on 7-of-13 shooting. He also pulled down 8 boards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;detroit-pistons-104--88-oklahoma-city-thunder&quot;&gt;Detroit Pistons 104 – 88 Oklahoma City Thunder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oklahoma City’s struggle to score came up big in this game again. This was yet another game in which Russell Westbrook had to carry the offensive load. He scored 33 points on 11-of-21 shooting. He limited himself to just 2 three-point attempts, and made 11 of his 12 free throw attempts. He also pulled down 15 rebounds and 8 assists. He spent much of the game in transition driving to the basket. His teammates seem content to mostly stand still in half-court offensive sets however. The team has very little offensive flow at the moment. There is not much movement getting into or out of the half-court sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jerami Grant and Enes Kanter were the only other Thunder players to score double-digits. Grant finished with 11 on 5-of-8 shooting. He grabbed 5 rebounds as well. Kanter scored 10 points on 4-of-9 shooting in just 16 minutes of game time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Victor Oladipo, who looked to have found an offensive rhythm, reverted to an ugly offensive game. He scored just 9 points on an atrocious 4-of-17 shooting. He attempted 7 shots from long range and made just 1 of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only team stat the Thunder won in this game was rebounding. The Thunder outrebounded the Pistons 51-47. But they shot far worse from the field and from distance than the Pistons, and lost the free throw percentage battle, despite making more free throws than Detroit even attempted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detroit was led by Tobias Harris and Aron Baynes. Harris scored 22 points while Baynes chipped in another 22 points. Kentavius Caldwell-Pope turned in a strong game for the Pistons as well putting up 17 points. The Pistons were without two of their starters this game as Reggie Jackson and Andre Drummond both sat out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time since the injury plagued season of 2014-2015, the Oklahoma City Thunder have lost four games in a row.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worrisome thing about this slide (other than the schedule really starts to get difficult in about 3 weeks) is that the Thunder defense has vanished. Coming into the game against Detroit, the Pistons were averaging about 97 points per game, yet the Thunder gave up 104 despite Detroit missing two starters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder also gave up 119 points to the Orlando Magic – a game in which former Thunder star Serge Ibaka scored a new career high. To put that in perspective, in 11 games this far in the season, the Magic have been limited to scoring games of 88 (a win against Washington), 80 (a loss at Chicago), 74 (a loss against Utah), and 69 (a loss at Indiana). In the same amount of minutes in a game, the Magic scored 50 more points against the Thunder than they did against the Indiana Pacers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving up these types of games to underperforming teams is not a way for the Thunder to make the playoffs. Right now, Russell Westbrook is getting no help on the offensive end of the court. If the other Thunder players want to carry their weight they need to play defense. Key Thunder players have disappointed offensively, namely Victor Oladipo and Steven Adams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adams has upped his scoring by 1.9 points per game over last season. This is tremendous growth, however the Thunder faithful were expecting a bigger jump this season. Adams has suffered from a hand injury most of the season, which has led to him dropping passes that he caught last season. These drops cost him and the Thunder scoring chances in the paint. Adams has looked slower and not as natural on the defensive end of the court this season as well, but he has remained a solid rebounder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Victor Oladipo is averaging just 15.2 points, 3.4 rebounds, and 1.5 assists per game. That’s the lowest scoring average since his rookie season, and his worst rebounding and assist numbers in his career. His shooting has been the biggest disappointment. He is making just 40% of his shots from the floor, 37.5% from three-point range, and a miserable 68.8% from the charity stripe. The only redeeming quality about his shooting percentages is that this season would be a career high from distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder need some type of help in spreading the floor. Defenses are packing the paint and focusing on making things difficult just for Russell Westbrook. While few defenses have been able to prevent Westbrook from scoring and putting up ridiculous stat lines, the strategy has worked in limiting his teammates’ effectiveness. Westbrook, Enes Kanter, and Oladipo are the only Thunder players scoring in double-digits on the season, with Steven Adams nearly joining the club (9.9 ppg).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across the rest of the league, every team has at least 3 double-digit scorers. The teams with 3 are Oklahoma City, Portland, Sacramento, Minnesota, New Orleans, Toronto, Milwaukee, and New York. Of those teams, just Oklahoma City, Portland, Toronto, and Milwaukee are currently in playoff positions. If Russell Westbrook is going to get no help from the rest of the team on the scoring end of the floor, his teammates must help prevent other teams from scoring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-16-2016/This-Week-In-Review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-16-2016/This-Week-In-Review/</guid>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Week In Review (11/2-11/9)</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;games&quot;&gt;Games&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-thunder-85---83-los-angeles-clippers&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Thunder 85 - 83 Los Angeles Clippers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder started the first quarter strong this time around, which has grown to be a rarity so far this season, but the Thunder couldn’t quite finish the strong start and barely lost the first quarter 24-23 on the back of a Mo Speights 7-0 scoring run to end the quarter. The Thunder were hitting shots and flying around on defense to disrupt the high-flying Clippers. Leading up to this game, Ersan Ilyasova was often Billy Donovan’s first substitute of the game. Ilyasova was traded early in the week though. Joffrey Lauvergne seems to have adopted the role that Ilyasova played coming in during the first quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first half of this game featured the first Thunder minutes of the season for two players. Nick Collison came off the bench in the second quarter to guard Blake Griffin who was abusing the Thunder bigs on the low block. The veteran came in and slowed the Clippers’ big man down.  Jerami Grant also got his first Thunder minutes after being acquired in a trade for Ilyasova just one day prior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bench struggled to score in this game, but that was the thought process about this team leading up to the season. The second unit should improve when Cameron Payne returns from his foot injury. It would be great to see the Thunder develop a system like the San Antonio Spurs. An offense that can be run by anybody (next man up mentality) would help this second unit tremendously and strip away the pressure of requiring a bench player to go make a play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a gritty win for the Thunder. Down by two points with 4:55 left in the fourth, rookie Domantas Sabonis hit a three pointer and gave the Thunder a 79-78 lead. The Thunder never looked back and remained in the lead for the final 4:55 of the game. Russell Westbrook sealed the win with a pull up jumper from the elbow to put the Thunder up 85-81. The Clippers scored once more on a DeAndre Jordan layup, but ultimately ended up falling short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westbrook was once again the only Thunder player to score in double digits. He scored 35 points, grabbed 6 rebounds, and dished out 5 assists. Steven Adams had a disappointing scoring game with just 2 points, but he pulled down 11 rebounds. Enes Kanter shot poorly as well, going just 3-11 from the field for 6 points. He carried his weight around the rim though by getting 12 rebounds. He has not started out great on the offensive end, but he still has a great nose for the ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;golden-state-warriors-122---96-oklahoma-city-thunder&quot;&gt;Golden State Warriors 122 - 96 Oklahoma City Thunder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second night of a back-to-back the Thunder had a tall task going up against the Golden State Warriors. It was the first game in which Kevin Durant was in the other team’s starting line up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder played probably their best first quarter of the season and were up by 1 point after the first 12 minutes. It was not to last however. The Warriors started a scoring run to close the gap at the end of the first quarter and the momentum carried over big time into the second quarter. The Thunder scored a measly 11 points, while Golden State scored 37. This would end up being the deficit for the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scoring was more even in this game with four players getting into double digits. Russell Westbrook logged another double-double scoring 20 points, and 10 assists. He was not efficient from the floor however. He shot just 4-15, but hit 10 of his 14 free throws. Victor Oladipo had his best game as a member of the Thunder. He scored 21 points on 8-13 shooting. Perhaps he hasn’t adjusted to playing for a contender yet, but the Thunder need him to put up these kinds of numbers on a nightly basis, and not just in blowouts. Steven Adams was the only Thunder player to put up a positive plus/minus score in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second nights of back to backs are always tough in this league – particularly when you’re playing two of the top three teams in the conference. The Thunder got a gritty win against the Clippers and followed that up with this dud of a game. But worry not, Thunder fans. The Warriors, on a second night of a back to back, lost by 20 to the lowly Los Angeles Lakers. Blowouts happen, and they can happen to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-thunder-112---92-minnesota-timberwolves&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Thunder 112 - 92 Minnesota Timberwolves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a good recovery game for the Thunder. Oklahoma City finally returned home after a short west coast road trip. The first half was hard fought by both teams and was relatively close with the Thunder taking a 6-point lead into halftime. Oklahoma City came out hungry in the third though and blew the game open. The Thunder won the quarter 31-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russell Westbrook scored 28 points efficiently. He shot 9-18 from the floor, including making four of his five three-point attempts. He also logged 8 assists and 6 rebounds. Steven Adams was the most efficient with his scoring this game though finishing with 14 points and making six of his 7 shots. He also grabbed 8 rebounds. Enes Kanter had a break out game to get a double-double. He scored 20 points on 9-14 shooting and pulled down 10 rebounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a good win over a young team that expects to challenge for a playoff spot this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-thunder-97---85-miami-heat&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Thunder 97 - 85 Miami Heat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dion Waiters made his return to Oklahoma City to a roar of applause. Waiters quickly worked his way into the hearts of Thunder fans during his short time in OKC. He did not have a great return. He only scored 2 points on 1-of-9 shooting in 27 minutes. However, Clay Bennett stuck around and made sure to give Dion a handshake after the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russell Westbrook logged another double-double scoring 14 points and 11 assists. He shot the ball poorly though shooting just 5-of-16 from the floor and making just 1 of 6 3 point attempts. Enes Kanter had the best game of any of the Thunder players. He scored 24 points on an incredibly efficient 10-of-12 shooting. He also made all 4 of his free throws, and grabbed 10 rebounds. It was his 3rd double-double of the season. Victor Oladipo had another solid game as well scoring 17 points on an efficient 6-of-9 shooting. Domas Sabonis got his first NBA double-double of his career. He scored 15 points and grabbed 10 rebounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;toronto-raptors-112---102-oklahoma-city-thunder&quot;&gt;Toronto Raptors 112 - 102 Oklahoma City Thunder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a tough game for the Thunder. They were playing good basketball, but seem to always struggle against Toronto in the Peake. The Thunder closed the gap to just 4 points with a little over 4 minutes left in the game at 99-95. Russell Westbrook had two turnovers in a row then missed a deep three point attempt that would’ve made even Stephen Curry blush. The Raptors then went on a 8-0 run to extend the lead and the Thunder never were able to regain a sense of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scoring was more balanced in this game however. Russell Westbrook scored 36 points and added 7 rebounds, and 7 assists. He did however have 8 turnovers, two of them being during a crucial comeback attempt. He shot just 9-of-26, including 3-of-12 from long distance. The redeeming factor of this game for Westbrook was that he was able to get to the line 18 times, and made 15 of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Victor Oladipo had another good scoring game, contributing 18 points, and 8 rebounds, but he did so on a poor shooting night making just 6 of his 16 attempts. He was 5-of-9 from deep though. If he can get the 3 ball to fall things will open up on the offensive end for both him and Westbrook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steven Adams had his second double-double of the season. He scored 14 points on 3-of-5 shooting. He also made all 8 of his free throw attempts. Adams seems to have made real progress from the stripe this season and has missed just one free throw through the first 8 games of the year. Adams pulled down 12 rebounds to round out his double-double.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-11-2016/This-Week-In-Review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-11-2016/This-Week-In-Review/</guid>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coming This Week (11/2-11/9)</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;games&quot;&gt;Games&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-thunder-at-los-angeles-clippers&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Thunder at Los Angeles Clippers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gametime: Wednesday, November 2, 2016, 9:30PM CST&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be the first real test for our beloved Thunder this season in a battle of the last unbeaten teams in the Western Conference. The Clippers have started the season 3-0 with a solid win over the Portland Trailblazers. The Clips also handily defeated the Phoenix Suns, who took the Thunder to overtime at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder will have to show they can hit jumpers and the 3-ball in this matchup. The Clippers have two exceptional interior players in Blake Griffin and Deandre Jordan - both of whom are averaging double-doubles early in the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-thunder-at-golden-state-warriors&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Thunder at Golden State Warriors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gametime: Thursday, November 3, 2016, 9:30PM CST&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the eyes in the NBA will be on this game. It is the first matchup between the Thunder and the traitorous Kevin Durant. The combination of having to watch Kevin Durant wear another team’s uniform, plus the very ugly way in which this game could finish will make it tough for the Thunder faithful to watch. However, Russell Westbrook will be well worth the two and a half hours of watching the game. He will most likely be attempting to make the universe implode (hopefully by dunking on Durant). Durant and Draymond Green are both averaging double-doubles early in the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please don’t abuse your TVs during this game. It’s a long season and we will still have 77 games after this one to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-thunder-vs-minnesota-timberwovles&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Thunder vs. Minnesota Timberwovles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gametime: Saturday, November 5, 2016 6:00PM CST&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minnesota will be our first home game after our first west coast road trip of the season. The Timberwolves are an exciting up-and-coming team who will likely challenge for a playoff spot this season. They have gotten off to a slower start than expected, losing 2 games by a combined 7 points. The Wolves have 3 rookie contract players averaging double digit scoring plus Gorgui Dieng who just signed a rookie extension a few days ago. They also have a new head coach in Tom Thibodeau formerly of the Chicago Bulls. This will not be the cupcake game that the Thunder would be hoping for following back to back games against the LA CLippers and Golden State Warriors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-thunder-vs-miami-heat&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Thunder vs. Miami Heat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gametime: Monday, November 7, 2016 8:00PM CST&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dion Waiters is making his return to Oklahoma City for the first time. In his short stint with the Thunder he quickly became a fan favorite. Miami is another young team that has suffered two close defeats (Charlotte, San Antonio). Hassan Whiteside is averaging a double-double early in the season. The team is coached by Erik Spoelstra, who Thunder fans may remember from the 2012 NBA Finals when the Heat defeated the Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder traded F Ersan Ilyasova and a protected first round draft pick to the Philadelphia 76ers in exchange for SF Jerami Grant on November 1st. It will be interesting to to see how the rotations change. Ilyasova was one of the first players off the bench for Coach Billy Donovan this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jerami Grant is an athletic and long small forward in his third year out of Syracuse. He is averaging 8.0 points per game, 3.5 rebounds, and 2 blocks this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NBA currently seems to be in a cycle of wanting to open up the court and play from behind the 3-point arc. The Thunder seem to be going in reverse of the rest of the NBA. Jerami Grant, Victor Oladipo, Russell Westrbook, and Andre Roberson are all athletic guards/forwards who excel on the defensive end, but do not shoot the 3 all that well. They are more than capable of disrupting the passing lanes and jump shots that most teams around the league are relying on now. It will be interesting to see if this is the course the Thunder are taking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people seem to think that this trade was part of a larger move that will be coming down the road before the trade deadline hits in February. Keep an eye out for other moves from the Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever and always, Thunder up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-02-2016/Weekly-Preview/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-02-2016/Weekly-Preview/</guid>
        
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Week In Review (10/25-11/1)</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;games&quot;&gt;Games&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-thunder-103-97-philadelphia-76ers&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Thunder 103-97 Philadelphia 76ers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a tough first game for the Thunder. We have a team in Oklahoma City this year that has a ton of new faces including two new starters and a position change for Andre Roberson. Rookie Domantas Sabonis and 3rd year man Victor Oladipo got their first starts in the orange and blue of Oklahoma City. 
  The Thunder got off to a slow start against the young, lottery riddled 76ers. Going into halftime the Thunder were tied with a team that won just 10 games last season. By the end of the third quarter the Thunder found themselves down 6 points. But on the back of a strong fourth quarter the Thunder squeaked out a 6 point win. The 76ers got an impressive performance from Joel EMbiid in his NBA debut. Embiid scored 20 points on 6-16 shooting, while also pulling down 7 boards in just 22 minutes of game action. 
  Russell Westbrook nearly logged a season opening triple-double. Westbrook scored 32 points (11-21; 1-2), grabbed 12 rebounds, and dished out 9 assists. Enes Kanter managed another Thunder double-double in 24 minutes off the bench. He scored 17 points and pulled down 12 rebounds on an efficient 7-14 shooting. Steven Adams also scored in double digits with 16 on 7-16 shooting. He also had 5 rebounds. 
  Victor Oladipo had a less than stellar Thunder debut. He scored just 10 points on a relatively terrible 4-16 shooting. He did however show up late in the fourth quarter making key defensive plays - including drawing a charge late in the quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-thunder-113-110-phoenix-suns-ot&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Thunder 113-110 Phoenix Suns (OT)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game was a thriller to entertain the first Thunder home crowd of the 2016-2017 season. Unfortunately, the Thunder got off to another slow start. The Suns outscored the Thunder 40-25 in the first quarter. The Suns couldn’t miss a shot.
  Behind Russell Westbrook’s back-breaking - if inefficient - 51 point, 13 rebound, and 10 assist triple-double the Thunder managed to make another comeback win. This was the first 50 point triple-double since Kareem Abdul-Jabbar had one in 1975. Victor Oladipo had a much better second game for the Thunder. He finished with 21 points and 5 rebounds. Oladipo and Westbrook were the only Thunder players to score double digits. In an interesting turn of events, Kyle Singler ended up with the highest plus/minus score for the Thunder logging a +21. 
  The Thunder showed a weakness when it came to perimeter defense though. T.J. Warren scored 30 points. Eric Bledsoe finished with 17. Devin Booker scored 21, and Brandon Knight scored 19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-thunder-113-96-los-angeles-lakers&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Thunder 113-96 Los Angeles Lakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder moved to 3-0 in the opening week after defeating the LA Lakers on the first Sunset Sunday of the season. This was the first game in which the Thunder looked like a complete team.
  Russell Westbrook logged his second triple-double of the season in an efficient fashion. He scored 33, grabbed 12 rebounds, and dished out an impressive 16 assists. Victor Oladipo still hasn’t found his shooting touch but he did manage to score 20 points. Steven Adams recorded his first double-double of the season on 14 points and 12 rebounds. Enes Kanter scored 16 points on an incredibly efficient 8-11 shooting and grabbed 6 rebounds in just 22 minutes of game time. 
  Kanter and Domantas Sabonis were the only Thunder players to have a negative plus/minus score. Ersan Ilyasova managed a +8 despite missing every shot he took and failing to score a single point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder have had trouble finding the stroke from beyond the three point line. After the first 3 games of the season, the Thunder are shooting a dismal .290 from deep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is good news though, Thunder fans. Victor Oladipo and Steven Adams both re-signed with the team. Oladipo signed a 4 year/$84 million contract extension, while the Big Kiwi signed for 4 years/$100 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever and always, Thunder up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Salutations, mate! Fare thee well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-01-2016/This-Week-In-Review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-01-2016/This-Week-In-Review/</guid>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Season Opening Thoughts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight is the night we’ve been waiting for since May 30th. Our season came crashing to an end after having a 3-1 series lead on the NBA’s best regular season team in history. Not to mention the defending NBA champions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the heartbreak of the 2016 Western Conference Finals Thunder fans were immediately thrown into a world of worry. There were clashing feelings as NBA fans everywhere wondered if Kevin Durant would stay or would he go? He went. On July 4th he announced he was joining the Golden State Warriors – just to get blown out on opening night by the tried and true San Antonio Spurs. While the Thunder made a number of offseason moves, losing Durant was clearly the largest. Serge Ibaka was moved on draft day, and Dion Waiters took his talents to South Beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now we get to see where this team is headed. We get to see Russell Westbrook finally be the unquestioned leader of this team. We get to see him be the unquestioned best player on a team for arguably the first time in his career going back to college. Thunder fans have focused on seeing Russell Westbrook tear up the league like he did when Durant missed most of the season with a foot injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also been excited about seeing Steven Adams play a more integral role in the offense and continue to improve dramatically from season to season. There are quite a few new faces from rookies Alex Abrines, Domantas Sabonis, and Semaj Christon to some newly signed veterans in Joffrey Lauvergne and Ersan Ilyasova. The most exciting new face to join the Thunder came to us in exchange for Serge Ibaka. His name is Victor Oladipo and for the last three seasons he’s been my favorite non-Thunder player to watch. He’s an exciting, slashing guard that seems as if he will fit in perfectly with the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder does not have a difficult schedule to start the season, but with so many new pieces it make take a few weeks for the team to gel and figure each other out. Look for Russell Westbrook, Steven Adams, and Enes Kanter to carry the load early while the new guys figure out the system and tendencies of the longer tenured Thunder players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may be biased, but I have higher expectations for this Thunder team than most of the national (and even local) sports pundits seem to have. I think this team easily wins 50+ games and has a first round home court advantage in the playoffs. I am not sold on the LA Clippers being the third best team in the Western Conference and could see the Thunder challenging for that spot. Third place through fifth place will likely end up being a toss up between the Thunder, Clippers and Trailblazers, but that requires all three teams to stay healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to be in for a fun ride this season, Thunder fans. Just remember the season is 82 games long. Don’t be reactive. Billy Donovan has a true opportunity to shape this team in a way that plays his style of basketball without having to cater to Kevin Durant’s flimsy will in trying to get him to stay. This team will be unlike any other we have seen in Oklahoma City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever and always, Thunder up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/10-26-2016/2016-Season-Opening-Thoughts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/10-26-2016/2016-Season-Opening-Thoughts/</guid>
        
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Offseason Timeline</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Oklahoma City Thunder’s season ended on May 30th this year. However, as soon as the season ended every member of the Thunder faithful could only think about one question: Would Kevin Durant re-sign with the team and continue building Oklahoma City into an image of stability. We all know the answer now. It was no. However, the offseason proved to be an active one. In honor of media day on Friday, September 23 and team training camp opening on Saturday, September 24, we have compiled a quick recap of the Thunder’s notable offseason roster moves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dates--moves&quot;&gt;Dates &amp;amp; Moves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June 23, 2016 - The Oklahoma City Thunder deal PF/C Serge Ibaka to the Orlando Magic in exchange for G Victor Oladipo, PF Ersan Ilyasova, and 2016 11th Overall draft pick C Domantas Sabonis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;July 1, 2016 - Free agency officially begins. F Kevin Durant, G Randy Foye, C Nazr Mohammed, and G Dion Waiters all become free agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;July 4, 2016 - Kevin Durant singlehandedly attempts to ruin American independence. He announces he will sign with the Golden State Warriors via the Player’s Tribune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;July 23, 2016 - G/F Alex Abrines (2nd Round, 2013) agrees to make the move from Spain to the NBA. He joins the OKC Thunder from Barcelona FC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August 4, 2016 - Russell Westbrook proves to be the heart and leader of the OKC Thunder and signs a 2-year contract extension to remain in Oklahoma City. Westbrook eases the stomachs of the Thunder faithful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August 12, 2016 - Domantas Sabonis signs rookie deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August 13, 2016 - The OKC Thunder agrees to a two-year deal with G Ronnie Price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August 20, 2016 - The OKC Thunder agree to terms with G Semaj Christon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August 30, 2016 - The OKC Thunder trades two 2017 Second Round draft picks to the Denver Nuggets in exchange for C Joffrey Lauvergne.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/09-22-2016/Offseason-Timeline/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/09-22-2016/Offseason-Timeline/</guid>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Way Too Quick Overreaction</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bad&quot;&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this game was really bad. Tonight the Thunder dropped Game 1 to the San Antonio Spurs 124-92. There was exactly one good thing about tonight’s game. Serge Ibaka seemed to have found a little bit of an offensive rhythm. He finished as the high scorer for the Thunder with 19 points on 8-15 shooting. He even made 3 of his 6 attempts from beyond the arc. Unfortunately he got absolutely roasted by LaMarcus Aldridge on the defensive end. Aldridge finished with 38 points. He shot 18-23 meaning that he missed fewer shots than Cameron Payne took all game (6).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Durant and Russell Westbrook combined for 30 points - fewer than Aldridge - on 11-34 shooting. That equates to 32.4% shooting from the floor. Those types of numbers are reminiscent of Game 2 against the Mavericks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder had just four players score in double digits: Ibaka (19), Durant (16), Westbrook (14), and Waiters (11).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder had just three players with a positive +/- : Randy Foye (+6), Anthony Morrow (+5), and Nazr Mohammed (+3). None of them played more than 10 minutes. Foye logged exactly 10 minutes. Mohammed played 4 minutes, and Morrow played for 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LaMarcus Aldridge had a career day. Kawhi Leonard did Kawhi Leonard things and finished with 25 points on an unbelievably efficient 10-13 shooting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A turtle had a better chance of guarding the pick and roll than the Oklahoma City Thunder tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fixes&quot;&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we have to fix the pick and roll defense. Tonight it was absolutely atrocious. I have watched a lot of basketball, but never have I seen a team refuse to switch, or fight over a screen like this team. The Thunder half-ass hedge on the screen, but the hedge is never held long enough to make a difference. The slip is always open. If an actual effort is made by the on-ball defender then the pop or roll is always open. The scariest thing about the pick and roll defense tonight is that it is the same scheme and defense we played all season. Billy Donovan has not changed the scheme over 86 games. It is worrisome that he may not change it after the 87th and moving forward. This Spurs team is dangerous and these types of things cannot be overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donovan should make a change in philosophy to either switch every screen or fight over every screen. The Thunder has the athletes to switch and effectively guard the pick and roll. The Thunder also has the interior presence to give up the drive off the pick and be able to alter a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-takeaway&quot;&gt;The Takeaway&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder played really terribly. It was probably the worst game they have played this season. They got absolutelly blown out by a veteran team that is coached by the best coach in the NBA. However, the Thunder still have two guys on the team who go by the names Kevin Durant and Russell Westbrook. KD and Westbrook will not allow this to happen again and will likely come out hungry and angry in Game 2 on Monday night. The real question that must be answered is whether or not Billy Donovan has the chops to make mid-series changes. He has to address the pick and roll defense at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever and always, Thunder up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/04-30-2016/Way-Too-Quick-Overreaction/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/04-30-2016/Way-Too-Quick-Overreaction/</guid>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Series Preview</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;last-series-for-the-san-antonio-spurs&quot;&gt;Last Series for the San Antonio Spurs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The San Antonio Spurs (67-15; 4-0) began their playoff journey this season with a 4 game sweep of the Memphis Grizzlies (42-40; 0-4). The closest the Grizzlies came to the Spurs was a 9-point loss in Game 3. The Spurs average margin of win was 22.5 points. It was mostly a defensive series, as you would expect from these two teams. San Antonio held Memphis to just 81 points per game - including a series low 68 points in Game 2. The Spurs managed to average 103 points per game. Kawhi Leonard was responsible for a little over 20% of the team’s scoring, as he averaged 21.5 points per game. The Spurs had just 3 other players to average double digit scoring during the series against the Grizzlies. LaMarcus Aldridge averaged 14.5 points per game. Patty Mills averaged 10.5 and Kevin Martin averaged exactly 10 points per game. Martin played in just two of the games in the series, however, and averaged just 14.5 minutes. In the Spurs complete domination of the Grizzlies, Zach Randolph and Lance Stephenson were the two highest scoring Grizzlies. The two averaged 13 points per game each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;key-players&quot;&gt;Key players&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thunder&quot;&gt;Thunder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;serge-ibaka&quot;&gt;Serge Ibaka&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serge Ibaka has always played a huge role for the Thunder in playoff series against the Spurs. Ibaka was injured going into the 2014 Western Conference Finals and the Thunder went down 0-2 in the series. Ibaka found a way to miraculously cure a Grade 2 strain of his left calf muscle and fought his way back to the line up. In his Game 3 return, Ibaka scored 15 points (6-7), pulled down 7 rebounds, and blocked 4 shots. The game staved off the threat of a sweep and energized the Thunder team who went on to tie the series 2-2 before ultimately falling 4-2 to the 2014 NBA Champion Spurs. In that series, Ibaka averaged 11.5 ppg, 5.3 rpg, and 3.3 blocks per game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This series the Thunder will need Ibaka to take advantage of the Spurs’ aging big men – Tim Duncan, David West, and Boris Diaw – and defend a player who will undoubtedly go down as one of the greats. His interior defense will be key to Thunder success as well. The Thunder will look to Ibaka (and Steven Adams) to alter Kawhi Leonard and Tony Parker’s shots in the paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;russell-westbrook&quot;&gt;Russell Westbrook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder will need the all-star point guard to show up in a big way this series. The Spurs point guards do not stand a chance of being able to guard Westbrook for an entire game. Oklahoma City will look to Westbrook to take advantage of the opponent while Kawhi Leonard does his best to try to slow down Kevin Durant. Look for Westbrook to absolutely abuse Tony Parker early in games. He will likely take Parker down to the block and try to get some good looks early. It will force the Spurs defense to react and put some early pressure on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dion-waiters--enes-kanter&quot;&gt;Dion Waiters &amp;amp; Enes Kanter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bench combo will be crucial for the Thunder to be successful. If the Dion Waiters of Games 3, 4 and 5 shows up then the Thunder likely win the bench game against the Spurs. However, if Waiters plays like he did in Games 1 and 2 then the Thunder are in trouble. The Thunder needs Waiters to be able to take advantage of Manu Ginobili and win the battle of bench shooting guards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanter is the anchor of the second unit. In four games this season against the Spurs, Kanter averaged 15.8 ppg and 14.8 rpg. The Thunder will desperately need him to keep up that level of play to have a chance in this series. The battle of the interior will go a long way in determining who will ultimately take this series. Look for Kanter to take advantage of smaller defenders from the bench unit. He is bigger, younger, and more active than either David West or Boris Diaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kevin-durant&quot;&gt;Kevin Durant&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duh. He’s the face of the franchise and seeking to remind everybody that he firmly belongs in the discussion of best players on the planet. This could be a great series for him to make that claim. He will likely spend a good amount of time being guarded by the NBA Defensive Player of the Year. The Thunder needs Durant to wear Leonard down so that Leonard’s offense is affected negatively. It is difficult to guard one of the world’s best and score 20+ points in a game. The Spurs need both aspects of Leonard’s game to beat the Thunder. Durant has improved from game to game this season against the Spurs. He averaged 27 ppg, and 6.7 rpg. The most encouraging thing for Thunder fans is that Durant shot 46.9% from the floor. In each successive game he shot better from the floor and scored more points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;spurs&quot;&gt;Spurs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kawhi-leonard&quot;&gt;Kawhi Leonard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As easy as it is for Thunder fans to dislike the Spurs, it is hard to dislike Leonard. The kid is a beast who excels at both ends of the court. He is the player that every coach wants to fill out his team. On the season he averaged 21.1 ppg, and 6.8 rpg, while also winning the Defensive Player of the Year award. He will be given the looming task of guarding Kevin Durant who will put Leonard through his paces. In&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;predictions&quot;&gt;Predictions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best chance for this Thunder team to win the series is to go 6 games. The Spurs were great at home this season and a Game 7 in San Antonio would be even more difficult. The Spurs and Thunder split the season 2-2 with both teams winning only on their home courts. The ideal situation is to win this one at home in Oklahoma City in Game 6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two times that the Spurs and Thunder have faced each other in the playoffs the series has gone at least 6 games. This is the first time the two teams have played earlier than the Western Conference Finals and it is the first time the two teams have not been the top two seeds in the conference. It should be a fun series. The Thunder will have to break down one of the historically great defenses, but Oklahoma City has the talent to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever and always, Thunder Up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/04-30-2016/This-Series-Preview/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/04-30-2016/This-Series-Preview/</guid>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Series in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;scores&quot;&gt;Scores&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;game-1---oklahoma-city-thunder-108---70-dallas-mavericks&quot;&gt;Game 1 - Oklahoma City Thunder 108 - 70 Dallas Mavericks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;game-2---dallas-mavericks-85---84-oklahoma-city-thunder&quot;&gt;Game 2 - Dallas Mavericks 85 - 84 Oklahoma City Thunder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;game-3---oklahoma-city-thunder-131---102-dallas-mavericks&quot;&gt;Game 3 - Oklahoma City Thunder 131 - 102 Dallas Mavericks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;game-4---oklahoma-city-thunder-119---108-dallas-mavericks&quot;&gt;Game 4 - Oklahoma City Thunder 119 - 108 Dallas Mavericks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;game-5---oklahoma-city-thunder-118---104-dallas-mavericks&quot;&gt;Game 5 - Oklahoma City Thunder 118 - 104 Dallas Mavericks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;series-recap&quot;&gt;Series Recap&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Oklahoma City Thunder won its first series in the 2016 NBA playoffs by a margin of 4-to-1. It was the team’s first foray into the postseason since the 2013-2014 playoffs when the Thunder lost to the San Antonio Spurs in the Western Conference Finals. Much has changed since the Thunder’s last playoff appearance. Golden State was still an up and coming team that slid into the playoffs as a 6 seed. The San Antonio Spurs were the number one overall seed that season with Kawhi Leonard beginning to fully assert himself as the future of the franchise by winning the NBA Finals MVP. Oh, and some guy named LeBron James still had his talents resting in South Beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first series was a hard fought one that got chippy on both sides. For two teams that are so close in geographic proximity, there was definitely no love lost. Kevin Durant was assessed a Flagrant 2 and ejected near the end of Game 4 for a slap to rookie Justin Anderson’s face. Justin Anderson himself received a post-game Flagrant 2 for his actions during Game 5 when he dove elbow first into Russell Westbrook’s face in the waning seconds of the game. Raymond Felton deliberately threw an elbow into Steven Adams’s side while Adams was attempting to block Felton out. It’s not Steven’s fault that Raymond Felton looks like, and is about the same height as, a Big Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder overall played a strong series. In their four wins no game was closer than 11 points. The average winning margin for the Thunder over the Mavericks was 23 points per game. The one game that the Mavericks managed to steal from the Thunder was Game 2. The Mavericks took the game, in Oklahoma City nonetheless, by a narrow 85-84 margin. It took a historically bad night from Kevin Durant and Russell Westbrook, and a Steven Adams put-back that was 0.1 seconds too late to win on the road by just one point. In Game 2, Kevin Durant shot just 7-33 from the floor managing to scrape together just 21 points. Russell Westbrook was 8-22 for just 19 points; however, he did pull down 14 rebounds. This game was a fluke from the Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real games to look at in the series are Games 1 and 3. The first game blowout makes sense looking at it in hindsight. While nobody predicted a 38-point blowout, everyone expected the Thunder to come out amped up. It was the first playoff game in 2 years and the Chesapeake Energy Arena was pumping. The Thunder could have come out nervous, but the core group of guys – Kevin Durant, Russell Westbrook, Serge Ibaka, and Nick Collison – who were on the team during the 2012 NBA Finals run were not going to allow that. This season’s roster includes many young guys who had never previously been to the playoffs. Dion Waiters, Kyle Singler, and Anthony Morrow are the biggest names who have never been to the postseason. Along with them, the rookies, Cameron Payne and Josh Heustis, have also clearly never been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enes Kanter has been to the playoffs one time previously following the 2011-2012 season. However, this season is Kanter’s first extended exposure to playoff basketball. In 2012, his rookie season, he played four games in which the Utah Jazz were swept by the San Antonio Spurs. Kanter played just over 10 minutes per game that series. Kanter posted a double-double in his debut scoring 16 points, and grabbing 13 rebounds, while shooting a ridiculous 7-10 from the floor. The playoff rookie shooting guards – Dion Waiters and Anthony Morrow – did not fare as well in their debuts. The two combined for just 11 points on 2-12 shooting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most encouraging sign from this game was the defensive intensity with which the Thunder played. They limited Dallas to just 70 points – a season low. Through the regular season the Mavericks averaged 93.8 points per game. The Thunder did well to force Dallas to miss shots. The Mavericks shot just 29.8% from the floor in Game 1 and just 22.2% from beyond the arc. This is the defense the Thunder needs in order to compete with the Golden State Warriors if the two teams meet in the Western Conference Finals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Game 3, the Oklahoma City Thunder offense absolutely erupted. The team scored 131 points tying a season high. The Thunder put 131 on two other teams this season. Both times occurred in wins on Dec. 29, 2015, against the Milwaukee Bucks (131-123) and on Feb. 9, 2016, against the Sacramento Kings (131-116). Game 3 saw Kevin Durant and Russell Westbrook assert their dominance as two of the top players in the NBA. Durant scored 34 points in 37 minutes, while shooting 11-25. Kevin Durant shot 44% from the floor and that feels low. I think the guy is doing something right. He also grabbed 7 rebounds. Westbrook pitched in 26 points and 15 assists. Dallas did manage to slow down Westbrook’s rebounding abilities though. The Mavericks prevented him from pulling down a rebound in the game. The last time that happened was this preseason against Fenerbahce. The last time it occurred during a game that counted was April 17, 2013, against the Milwaukee Bucks when he played just 7 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanter turned in another great game. He scored 21 points on 8-10 shooting, pulled down 8 rebounds, and blocked a shot, all in just 22 minutes of game time. This was a breakout game of sorts for Dion Waiters too. After shooting a combined 4-17 and totaling just 13 points in Games 1 and 2, Waiters broke out for 19 points on 7-11 shooting in Game 3. He even made 4 of his 8 3-point attempts. Waiters continued to play well through the end of the season logging double digit scoring nights in Games 3, 4, &amp;amp; 5 and shot 50% or higher in each of the three games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the type of offense the Thunder will need to bring if they want to beat the San Antonio Spurs in the Western Conference Semifinals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serge Ibaka was absolutely huge in this series. The Serge Ibaka that showed up against Dallas was the Serge Ibaka that Sam Presti chose over James Harden. Ibaka finally looked like a member of the Big 3 for OKC again and it was refreshing. He was consistent through the first four games of the series, with a dip in Game 5. In Games 1-4, Ibaka averaged 15.25 ppg, 7 rpg, and 1.5 bpg. He shot 71.4% from the floor and 66.7% from 3-pt. range. Ibaka looked confident through theses games. Game 5 was a terrible regression. He scored just 2 points (made 2 free throws) and failed to score a basket in the run of play. Serge Ibaka always shows up in a big way for Oklahoma City when playing the Spurs in the postseason. He will be a crucial component to the Thunder’s chances for success in the conference semifinals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever and always, Thunder Up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/04-29-2016/This-Series-In-Review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/04-29-2016/This-Series-In-Review/</guid>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
