<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thunder Op-Ed</title>
    <description>Welcome to Thunder Op-Ed! Come back often or follow us on twitter  for content, thoughts, and ramblings on your Oklahoma City Thunder. This site is independent of the OKC Thunder organization and all views expressed are that of the author.
</description>
    <link>http://thunderoped.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thunderoped.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 05:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 05:07:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Game Recap: Thunder vs. 76ers</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;okc---phi-85&quot;&gt;102 OKC - PHI 85&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight the Oklahoma City Thunder beat the Philadelphia 76ers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our hearts remain with Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-11-13/0.jpg&quot; title=&quot;French Flag (Source - Trey Shelton)&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:500px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 22:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-13-2015/game-recap-sixers1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-13-2015/game-recap-sixers1</guid>
        
        
        <category>phi</category>
        
        <category>recap</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eyeball Test: Thunder @ Wizards</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;okc-125---was-101&quot;&gt;OKC 125 - WAS 101&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder build on their good habits and blow out the Wizards to fend off the national media drooling over a Durant homecoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Great start again. This looks like a thing now. No matter the end result, the Thunder have consistently started very strong.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The got a little too comfortable and the risky passes/turnovers came back out. They got back on track pretty quickly though.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ibaka hit a mice running floater off the dribble. It looks very much under control, a vast improvement over the robotic-like attempts we’ve seen in past seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Roberson knocking down threes. The whole team shot ridiculously efficient from deep against Washington, but Roberson looks more confident in his shot in general.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Westbrook didn’t score until there were 5 minutes left in the first quarter. Instead he was lasering in passes from the top of the key to Durant standing by himself under the basket.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Durant is typically terrible in DC. His visit home with family and friends seems to distract him, although that’s completely speculation. This visit, however, with all the media attention and the Thunder (and Durant) working back into form he was locked in.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;McGary in the early bench rotation again. Great energy to start and had some good chemistry alongside D.J. Augustin.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Singler looked like he was having a more successful game, but it doesn’t change one thing: When he touches the ball, no matter where it is on the floor, it seems to bring the same results as Kevin Martin catching the ball in the corner several seasons ago. They both were likely to end in a turnover.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The bench, when Waiters isn’t being dominant, seems to lack a confidence it’s had since James Harden was drafted. The Thunder have always had an explosive ball handler coming off the bench that had the ability to drive, dish, and hit big shots. Harden is now in Houston of course, and Reggie Jackson is tearing it up in Detroit next to Andre Drummond. As the game progressed and Waiters was hitting his stride, the bench started to click. He’s making positive progress each game, and while his shooting percentages may not be sustainable, having ‘Contract Dion’ keep it up will be huge for the Thunder. Also, #contractdion looks weirdly similar to ‘contradiction’. Coincidences?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Adams was unlucky with the whistles, sitting early due to foul trouble twice during the game. It flipped the center rotation, putting Kanter with the starters and Adams with the bench. And he ate the Washington backup bigs. He was rebounding, or causing havoc underneath, it seemed like every play. Rebounding advantage with Adams and Kanter is a very good thing, and hopefully KD can come back and maintain his progress back to rebounding like he used to. He had 10 in the first half against Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I was worried about Ibaka’s defensive quickness last game. It’s still lingering, but when he’s on he looks just as good as he used to. Here’s hoping it’s just a spotty start to the season that will pick up to where his offense has been so far.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve alluded to it a few times, but Durant’s hamstring strain puts him out at least a week. Luckily there’s a two day break and a light schedule coming up, but an injured Durant is never good. He played after the obvious funny landing that hobbled him up, and he said it just felt sore after the game. Hopefully it doesn’t slow down his rounding into form very much. He was making huge strides up to this point.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Westbrook is one assist away from a triple double he has a one-track mind. He’s going to hit his teammates with passes until one of them makes a shot. It was getting later in the third quarter, and he knew he wouldn’t be playing in the fourth with the 20+ point blowout going strong. It took three empty trips down the court until someone could hit a shot. Westbrook then resumed scoring at will.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It would have been really nice to see the Thunder against a healthy Wizards team, but 97 points in three quarters means something is going right.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I get sad when Morrow misses 3-pointers. He also struggled defensively, but so did everyone in the fourth quarter. Because blowout.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;With such a huge lead I’m surprised there was no Cameron Payne sighting until 3:22 left in the game. He scored his first career points with a nifty driving scoop shot. He’s active on defense, but he’s not the strongest right now and has some definite work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eyeball-test&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t have much to say here. They blew out an injury riddled team that’s been the center of a building media frenzy trying to steal away the Thunder’s face. Westbrook did his thing, and Dion grew bigger in his sixth man role. Hopefully the Thunder can hold off teams this next week and Durant comes back healthy and ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 19:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-11-2015/okc-was-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-11-2015/okc-was-notes</guid>
        
        
        <category>was</category>
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>KD visits DC</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everybody in the world knows that Kevin Durant is going to be a free agent this summer. The NBA knows it. NBA fans know it. Oklahoma City knows it. Yet, the continual media fascination with his impending free agency is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Durant recently said that the Washington Wizards fans openly recruiting him during games when Oklahoma City - his current team, don’t forget - travels to the east coast. Yes, Durant is from DC and he loves his home town. Yes, he can choose to play anywhere in the world he wants next season. The media is so dead set on Durant being Lebron James and returning home that they can’t get out of their own way when discussing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today on PTI, Tony Kornheiser and Michael Wilbon addressed Durant’s homegoing. Two days after he said the Wizards fans were being disrespectful to their own team by openly lobbying another player to come to the city &lt;strong&gt;a year from now&lt;/strong&gt;, Wilbon stated that he wasn’t sure what Durant was doing. A man who always discusses his unfettered access to the biggest and best players in the NBA said that he couldn’t tell which way Durant was leaning. Did that stop him from giving his thoughts anyway? No. He did say, however, that Durant keeping DC at arm’s length may be an attempt to lessen the blow if he decides not to return home. He said it’s difficult to go home. Yes. Yes it is. Not everybody is Lebron James. What he failed to mention was that Kevin Durant is still playing in Oklahoma City. Maybe he was doing it because he actually likes this little part of the Mid-Southwest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kornheiser went on to say that Durant should re-sign for one year in Oklahoma City and then leave for the Los Angeles Lakers with Russell Westbrook during the summer of 2017. The one year contract, no matter what the long term results may become, is a sentiment others such as Zach Lowe have also expressed as Durant’s best move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody is giving Oklahoma City a chance. Yes - we are a small market. We are not LA, DC, or New York. We never will be. We don’t want to be, and today’s NBA has a global reach that has allowed OKC’s biggest stars to sign some of the most lucrative endorsement deals internationally. We don’t have the big fancy nightclubs, with celebrities and paparazzi. But what we do have is a loyal fanbase. This city supported a 1-12 team in its first year and has not looked back since. We know how lucky we are to have Durant and Westbrook. Sure, if you want to play in a city of 10+ million people, this isn’t your place. But if you want to play in front of a great fanbase who will show up every single night, filling the arena with a defeaning roar, then this is your place. If you want to be showered with constant praise, this is your place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever and always, Thunder Up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-10-2015/kd-visits-dc</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-10-2015/kd-visits-dc</guid>
        
        
        <category>durant</category>
        
        <category>oped</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Game Recap: Thunder vs. Suns</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;okc-124---pho-103&quot;&gt;OKC 124 - PHO 103&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder ended the first (and hopefully only) losing streak of the season. It was another Sunset Sunday with the Thunder wearing the new Sunday alternates. Oklahoma City put together a full game for the first time this season, winning three quarters and tying one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder came out blazing in the first quarter pushing the lead to 15 points before the second unit allowed the lead to slip. The starters combined for 19 points on 9-of-16 shooting while the second unit went just 3-of-9 for 8 points. Kevin Durant got hot immediately shooting 3-of-4 and scoring 8 in the quarter while Russell Westbrook went 3-of-6 for 6 points and added 6 assists as well. Eric Bledsoe had a huge quarter for the Suns making 6-of-7 from the floor and scoring 15 in the first frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second quarter saw the return of the first unit and a win for the quarter – outscoring Phoenix 31-25. Dion Waiters got things turned around shooting a perfect 3-of-3 from the field, and 4-of-4 from the charity stripe to score 10 in the quarter. The Thunder went into halftime leading 60-54.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second half was the big difference for the Thunder. They extended the lead to double digits again in the third quarter. The starters played significant minutes coming out of halftime, with the exception of Steven Adams who logged only 4:21 in the third with Enes Kanter relieving him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final quarter saw the Thunder push the lead to the eventual blowout that the game became. The bench was seen as a strength for the Thunder coming in to the season but it has been disappointing compared to the hype it received as possibly being the deepest team assembled in Oklahoma City. The second unit redeemed itself in the fourth quarter though. In the final quarter the reserves combined to go 8-of-11 for 20 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In just six minutes, Kevin Durant had a perfect quarter going 5-of-5 from the field (including a made three) for 11 points in just 6:34. Kanter tied Durant for leading scorer of the quarter shooting an efficient 5-of-5 and converting his only free throw after an a foul and made basket. Dion Waiters, not to be left out, joined the perfect quarter club and finished the quarter with 5 points on 2-of-2 shooting, including a basket from behind the arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Durant lead all scorers with a quiet 32 points on 12-of-19 shooting. He completed the double-double by pulling down 11 boards as well. Russell Westbrook joined Kevin Durant in the double-double club scoring 21 points on 9-of-20 shooting and dishing out 13 assists. It was his fourth game in a row with a double-double and his fifth overall on the season. Enes Kanter and Dion Waiters joined in the scoring fun from the bench. Kanter finished with 21 points while shooting 90 percent from the floor (9/10) and converting all 3 of his free throw attempts. He pulled down 7 rebounds too. Waiters pitched in 19 points on an efficient 6-of-9 shooting and forced 3 turnovers, reaching into the cookie jar for 3 steals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thunder fans continue to be baffled by Anthony Morrow’s absence from the rotation. He logged his first DNP-Coach’s Decision of the season, joining Nick Collison as the only players to leave their warmups on all game. Coach Billy Donovan attributed it to the matchups, though Morrow has not seen significant minutes the last 4 games. He failed to score in all 4 games in very playing time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder take on the Washington Wizards in a homecoming game for Kevin Durant on Tuesday, November 10th. The game will be carried by NBATV and Fox Sports Oklahoma with tipoff occurring at 6 pm Central Standard Time. Kevin Durant recently stated that the Washington fans openly attempting to court him before his looming free agency was “disrespectful” to the team they currently have. It should prove to be an interesting game. It could also be Billy Donovan’s first game against Bradley Beal who played for Donovan at Florida before leaving for the NBA. Beal is listed as questionable for the game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 21:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-09-2015/game-recap-suns1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-09-2015/game-recap-suns1</guid>
        
        
        <category>phx</category>
        
        <category>recap</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eyeball Test: Suns @ Thunder</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;phx-103---okc-124&quot;&gt;PHX 103 - OKC 124&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder haven’t lost to the Suns at home for a few seasons, and they were able to keep that streak alive with a very solid victory Sunday night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The start looked good yet again. Solid defense and movement on offense, just like the Thunder have started the last few games. The question was whether it could last or not.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Westbrook had two steals early in the first quarter, cheating off his man and sneaking around behind the ball handler to grab it away for fast break opportunities. As the game went on Westbrook kept trying for steals, often letting his man blow by him to try and poke it away from behind. Gambling from Westbrook can lead to those explosive, sometimes game changing plays, but there’s a nice balance to be had.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ibaka and Kanter fought over a rebound again this game, turning it over. This is the dumbest kind of turnover, but those two may average one a game this season.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The first few games Donovan seemed to be substituting out his lineups gradually, but more recently he’s been doing wholesale changes sitting the starters in bulk near the end of the first quarter. It hasn’t gone well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The great start to the game was completely negated by the bench. It was a collapse that has seen the Thunder spiral in several games. The double digit lead was completely erased, leaving the game tied heading into the second quarter. The turnover bug seemed to be about to strike again and Phoenix was blowing by the Thunder on defense. There’s too much talent on this bench for it to be this bad.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maybe stagger KD and Russ’ minutes early in the game if the bench can’t get into rhythm fast enough to stay off major losses in points?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Singler replaced Durant yet again. I think I almost understand why it theoretically makes sense, maybe. Waiters is already on the floor at this point, replacing Roberson as the first substitution. Waiters and Durant make the most logical 1-to-1 replacement, with ball-handling, scoring, and passing abilities. With Waiters already on the floor, however, Singler is the go to small forward replacement. However, when Durant sits why not just switch Waiters onto the opposing team’s 3? He has the size, and it would allow Donovan to bring in another guard (Morrow?) off the bench.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mitch McGary sighting early, and his struggles continued. Can’t get much floor time or get in rhythm when committing three fouls nearly instantly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Waiters stepped it up big time in the second quarter. He was the only bench production, and things really seemed to open up for him when Ibaka, and then Adams, checked back in to get some defensive stops, space the floor, and open Waiters up with good screens. The bench by itself wasn’t giving enough help to help Waiters get going.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It seems like the Thunder have collapsed in the latter half of the first quarter in multiple (if not most) games this season. The chemistry has been lacking when the bench takes over, and it doesn’t seem to regain a foothold until the starters have taken back over halfway through the second. It’s set up some very positive third quarters, but the team has lost big leads and good momentum in that late 1st, early 2nd chunk of the game. Against good teams this puts the Thunder in a hole early, and when Westbrook and Durant feel the pressure the chance of hero, iso ball gets a lot bigger. It’s happened three times already this season, and when the wheels fell off the bus they were never put back on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;McGary checked back into the game in the third quarter. He was getting torched by Markieff Morris, but he started to calm down in general and added his energy. The bench activity was significantly elevated from the first quarter. It was an overall effort, but McGary will always bring energy. There’s a chance Donovan put him into the rotation, despite his obvious struggles, against Phoenix to try and force him to get going so that he can be a spark ready to go whenever it’s needed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The bench was able to maintain the lead and positive play leading into the fourth. The injection of the skill and energy of Westbrook and Durant midway through absolutely killed Phoenix. The pressure was off with a decent lead to begin with, and the ball movement from the start of the game continued. Late in games the two superstars have had isolation tendencies, especially when the game is close. This is a major step forward in terms of late-game execution, but will it hold up when the pressure mounts? It’s at least a start in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ibaka seemed a step behind all night, and has for a good portion of these first seven games. I hate to even think about worrying if he’s lost a step defensively.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Post game Donovan discussed ‘established players’ being professional and understanding that it’s a big picture where new guys need the opportunity to get comfortable so they can better contribute in the long run. He was talking about Collison, but it could also have shed some light on the Morrow/Singler minutes discrepancy. Everyone knows what Morrow brings, and Singler has been absolutely terrible since arriving in OKC. Maybe Donovan is desperately trying to get Singler going before utilizing a more balanced approach between those two players. This would make the most practical sense in the minutes that almost seem force-fed to Singler.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eyeball-test&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comfortable and collected.&lt;/strong&gt; They shouldn’t have lost, and they didn’t. The good parts got better, and the turnovers and late game execution troubles are definitely on positive upswings. The bench is still unpredictable, however, and needs to be at least consistent for this team to make the dent in the West that its capable of making.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-09-2015/phx-okc-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-09-2015/phx-okc-notes</guid>
        
        
        <category>phx</category>
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eyeball Test: Thunder @ Bulls</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;okc-98---chi-104&quot;&gt;OKC 98 - CHI 104&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On national television the Thunder started strong against Chicago, but late in the game bad defense, stagnation, and a rejuvenated Derrick Rose led to another disappointing loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once again the Thunder started very strong out of the gate. Lock down defense and great movement on the offensive end without the gamble plays that lead to turnovers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ibaka started 4/4 from the field, Westbrook started a 16 assist night early on with good finds, and Durant looked much stronger on defense while holding his ground against Mirotic in the post. The big three all looked engaged and ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Thunder also ended up in late shot clock possessions twice in the first quarter where they didn’t panic. They continued to move and look for the open man, and both plays ended with a made basket before the shot clock ran out.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The defense inside to start was good, but 3-pointers from Chicago kept them in the game early.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Singler checked in for Durant. He continued to miss shots. I’ve mentioned this before (as has everyone covering the Thunder), but Singler’s minutes are very confusing. Morrow would be the likely player to get Singler’s minutes, but he hasn’t played well in the chances he’s receive either. The problem with that is, however, that the time Morrow sees on the floor is mostly without the starters where his perimeter spacing and catch and shoot abilities really stand out. He seems to be used in spots where he’s a cutter. Not the best use of Morrow.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why can’t this offense keep up it’s good play for more than 8 or 9 minutes. As the first quarter ended isolation plays took over and Westbrook at one point posted up too far out 3 plays in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Durant looked like he was struggling, and not because he was missing shots. He just looked out to lunch. There were several hard drives to the basket where he was frustrated with no-calls, and maybe this turned off his drive for a while. Jimmy Butler was also destroying Durant on defense at this point in the game. Durant kept losing him off the ball as his old habit of ball watching reared its head.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Durant won MVP it was when he was forced to not only be the most skilled player for OKC, but also it’s motor. He had to bring the energy that disappeared when Westbrook was out. It elevated his game, and he was so much more engaged. When Westbrook is on the floor Durant has a habit of receding into the background, and there’s times when it’s easy to forget he’s even on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After a while, Durant seemed to perk back up, and during the 3rd quarter he really stepped it up. The result? The Thunder went on an 8-2 run to tie the game.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kanter really is a beast on offense. He gives maximum effort and was the reason the Thunder were able to stay in the game for a lot of the fourth simply by getting offensive rebounds and second possessions. The problem was that he can’t switch on defense. Adams isn’t the fastest laterally, but a little bit goes a long way sometimes. Kanter was definitely trying, however, and with Adams out with back problems he did his best to contain Rose. Rose had a special kind of determination last night to finish the game though, and Brian Windhorst drumming up rumors in the press probably didn’t help the Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The defensive adjustments didn’t come quickly enough to end the game. The Thunder were getting beat whether Rose shot or passed the ball, and the Bulls were able to run the exact same play multiple times to build their lead.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Thunder looked overall much better against Chicago. The effort was much better, and they took much better care of the ball. The team just doesn’t look like it’s found its ‘identity’ yet, and some slip-ups in coverages didn’t help either. The attitude and look of this ball club seems to change every few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Donovan also needs to get a better handle on the roster and his lineups. He’s still figuring everything out, and it will definitely take time. Tape on the team can only teach you so much. It’s just disconcerting to see such a consistently dominant team over the past few years trying to figure out who it is.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eyeball-test&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confusing.&lt;/strong&gt; The Thunder are .500, and hopefully they’ve learned from the good and the bad to figure out their issues. Let’s just hope that addressing them one at a time doesn’t take too long and this team can get clicking sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-06-2015/okc-chi-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-06-2015/okc-chi-notes</guid>
        
        
        <category>chi</category>
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eyeball Test: Raptors @ Thunder</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;tor-103---okc-98&quot;&gt;TOR 103 - OKC 98&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder fall apart for a second game, turning the game over, literally, to Toronto in a sloppy, un-energetic loss. The turnovers continue to ruin spurts of very promising play and improving defense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After the loss to Houston, Durant said he needed to make a point to be a better leader and get his guys involved. He started the game looking to distribute, but it doesn’t help how much he passes to a wide open Roberson if he refuses to shoot the ball.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Very promising defensive effort to start. Toronto didn’t get any good looks, and it seemed to fuel the offense (Scott Brooks wasn’t lying all those years it turns out). You can see the potential of this team, it just hasn’t been sustainable for more than a quarter at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Adams seems like he’s getting better on offense every single game. He moves well in the pick-and-roll, and when he catches the ball it’s usually deep in the paint and results in an easy look.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Westbrook had 8 assists in the first quarter, and I feel like all of them were passes straight into the paint for easy looks. The offense was clicking to start this game even though the tempo was slower at times than this team wants to play at.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Kanter catches the ball anywhere near the basket it’s going up. Usually it’s a very good look, and Kanter has great moves in the post. Sometimes help comes, however, and he gets into trouble. And when more defenders get sucked in that means there’s a shooter open somewhere, and it would help if Kanter’s mind wasn’t entirely locked on scoring.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Singler. Good grief. 1. Fouls, fouls, fouls. 2. Absolute 0 on offense.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So much for no turnovers. The second quarter completely erased what the first had accomplished, and despite curbing them a bit in the third the train had already derailed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fouling continuously was adding to the turnovers, giving away free points. Way too many fouls.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This team could be frustrating for a good while. They have spurts of greatness, but there’s absolutely no consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At one point in the game Toronto was shooting 31% against OKC’s 50%, and the Thunder were +10 on rebounds. Somehow, the Thunder were only 6 points in the lead. A perfect example of how sloppy play is making winning a much harder task.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Morrow played over Singler (finally) in the fourth quarter. Singler was adding to the fouling epidemic, so it would have made no sense for him to see the floor, but it almost felt like that forced Donovan into playing Morrow. The lack of playing time for Morrow is very strange, especially proving what offensive spark he can bring last season and becoming a fan favorite. Donovan may be more talkative than Brooks, but what he’s actually thinking is just as mysterious (and maybe more so).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Absolutely zero urgency in the fourth quarter. Toronto should never have still been in the game, but they hung around because OKC never looked like they cared enough to put it away. They also didn’t score for the last 6 minutes of the game, which is unacceptable for any team. When you’ve allowed the opponent to go to the line twice the number of times you have, and you turn the ball over 19 times there’s no way you can get away with a scoreless finish to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kneejerk reactions are going to start flying about now, and it’s easy to see why. A learning curve will be hard for most fans to accept graciously, but when is it actually ok to start to worry? Donovan was brought in to bring some tactical skill on the offensive end that Brooks appeared to lack, but when are there too many X’s and O’s?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One last thing: When Rockets guard, Kyle Lowry, passed the ball to a referee after receiving a frustrating call he was given a technical foul, because the pass was “too hard and taken as a sign of aggression.” Seriously refs? Put your big boys pants on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eyeball-test&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inconsistent and lazy.&lt;/strong&gt; The Thunder have failed to impose their will on games by dictating tempo or style. Instead they’ve allowed their opponents to control the game, and despite the superior talent in OKC the turnovers and inconsistency across the board from minute to minute has plagued this team in a very bad way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-05-2015/tor-okc-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-05-2015/tor-okc-notes</guid>
        
        
        <category>tor</category>
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Game Recap: Raptors vs. Thunder</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;tor-103---okc-98&quot;&gt;TOR 103 - OKC 98&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turnovers destroyed the Thunder again tonight. It has been a common trope for Oklahoma City already this season. There is a learning curve when it comes to implementing a new offense, but after a full offseason, and now 5 games into the season there should be improvement. Unfortunately, when it comes to ball security there hasn’t been any improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder started the game out hot. They scored 23 in the first quarter while holding the Raptors to just 13. Kevin Durant went 3-6 to start and Russell Westbrook racked up 8 assists in the opening quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wheels fell off the bus in the second quarter though, and the roles got reversed. The Raptors put up 27 in the second quarter. Toronto only shot 44.4% in the quarter, but they got to the charity stripe 10 times, converting 9, compared to Oklahoma City’s just 2 trips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With both teams having a successful offensive and defensive quarter in the first half, the third quarter was an offensive explosion. Oklahoma City put up 42 points in the quarter and Toronto put in 33. Russell Westbrook had 16 points and 5 assists in the quarter. Kevin Durant scored another 11 points in the quarter. The team shot an outstanding 72.7% from the floor including 6/9 from deep. The biggest difference in this quarter was the turnovers. The team limited the freebies to just two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth quarter was borderline atrocious for Oklahoma City. The Thunder shot just 25% from the field and went 1/6 from the arc. Toronto took advantage of the poor shooting performance and closed the gap over the quarter, ultimately surpassing and defeating the Thunder. The Raptors fourth quarter was efficient. The team shot 50% from the floor and made 13 trips to the free throw line knocking down 11 of the attempts. The fourth quarter was a bit of an enigma when someone looks at the minutes. Dion Waiters played all twelve minutes of the quarter while Russell Westbrook and Kevin Durant played just 7:29 each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest take away from this game is that there is a pattern emerging. The Thunder still haven’t figured out late game execution. The offense became stagnant down the stretch. Instead of relying on the offense which saw Russell Westbrook hand out 15 assists in the first 3 quarters, the team began relying on one on one isolation plays again. The Scotty Brooks comparisons will now be prevalent for Billy Donovan until a successful late game offense emerges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder lost the lead inside of a minute left in the game. Kevin Durant took a turnaround fade away 14 foot jumper. Toronto rebounded the miss and Demar DeRozan converted a layup to put the Raptors up. Maybe the hardest part of the fourth quarter was when a jump ball came with 11 seconds left on the Thunder offensive end. Durant missed the back end free throw which Toronto rebounded. Westbrook made a hustle play and knocked the ball loose and Serge Ibaka jumped on the ball to tie it up. Ibaka should have won the tip, but miss-timed his jump essentially sealing the game for the Raptors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ibaka had an efficient night scoring 10 points on 4/7 shooting and pulled down 6 rebounds. Unfortunately that is not the stat line of a player that Westbrook and Durant rely on as a safety valve to relieve pressure. Enes Kanter continued to impress though. He finished with 15 points on 7/11 shooting and pulled down 6 rebounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder are still working on settling into the new system and new coach. Growing pains are expected when there are changes like these. Donovan is still adjusting to the NBA and his players are still adjusting to the new leadership at the top. The season is young and this team is going to be crazy good once they limit the turnovers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 23:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-04-2015/game-recap-raptors1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-04-2015/game-recap-raptors1</guid>
        
        
        <category>recap</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eyeball Test: Thunder @ Houston</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;okc-105---hou-110&quot;&gt;OKC 105 - HOU 110&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A desperate Rockets team reawoke its rivalry with the Thunder, allowing OKC to get emotional and sloppy and turn over the ball 24 times on the way to its first loss of the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Rockets were embarrassed, playing at home, playing against the Thunder which Harden always seems to get up for, and the Thunder were on the second night of a back-to-back. This screamed trap game from the tip.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Harden blocking Ibaka? That seems backward and not a good sign early in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ibaka seemed off to start the game. A step behind on defense and clumsy on rebounds. He came to life as the game progressed, however with his fair share of blocks and rebounds to help OKC build its lead in the first half. It may be up and down for Ibaka the first few weeks of the season. He’s either been really good or really off.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kyle “Foul Machine” Singler strikes again. Guarding Harden is foul trouble waiting to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Roberson and Singler saw time on the court together twice during the game. It seemed to work (somehow) in the first half, but that may have been more thanks to Waiters and Kanter however. When Donovan tried it again in the later part of the game it didn’t work so well, and he basically said so in his post game interview.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kanter blocked Harden, and then caused Howard to miss! Stop the presses! He seems to be improving on defense each game. He’s definitely trying.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;D.J. Augustin picked right up where he left off with great shooting. He did, however, have a few turnovers. He wasn’t the only one…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Durant’s one-on-one defense was great. He was blocking and altering shots regularly. He’s always had an uncanny ability to blow up a fast break, and it’s good to see that hasn’t changed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Harden and Durant were trading 3-pointers to end the half. This rivalry will always be strong as long as the main players remain in the mix, and somehow Patrick Beverly is included in that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The offensive rebounds in the first half were a big reason for the lead heading into the 3rd quarter. Ibaka and Adams were tearing it up under the basket, and the rebound advantage held for the Thunder the whole game. It should have been the reason the Thunder won the game, but there was another stat line that got in the way of that…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Turnovers. Good grief. It’s been sloppy since the season began, but against a skilled and fast team like the Rockets those turnovers will kill you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As is par for the course with these two teams, frustrations began to build about halfway through the 3rd quarter. Howard threw Westbrook down and started locking arms with everyone. Westbrook began to force himself and passes into places neither could fit. Combine that with taking a foul as Durant’s shoe came off and Westbrook had to sit with his fourth foul, which spiraled the team out of control.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The emotional control of this team is always on the brink of going over the edge of the cliff. With the raw energy Westbrook leads the team with it’s not hard to see why, but some coaches have the ability to stop the bleeding by recognizing the danger, calling a timeout, and potentially switching out players. Scott Brooks learned the necessity of this at times, especially against teams like the Rockets and Clippers. Other coaches like Popovich are always up off the bench when a big momentum shot goes against their team. Billy Donovan, did no such thing last night.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are obvious merits for Donovan’s fluid substitutions and calm game management, but sometimes a full stop is required. When the Thunder repeatedly gave the ball to the Rockets and momentum swung toward Houston in the 3rd, the Thunder continued to reel out of control. Westbrook was on the bench, and even the calming presence of Durant couldn’t change things. He was continually double-teamed and forced into turnovers as well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maybe Donovan didn’t fully understand the history between these two teams. Maybe he thinks a turnover is a turnover and the particular circumstances surrounding that part of the game don’t matter. Maybe he doesn’t like to make drastic changes in lineups and style, instead trying to get his players to correct their mistakes right then and there. It’ll be interesting to see what approach he takes the next time the Thunder lose their head and can’t get it back attached. I don’t think we’ll have that long to wait.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In other news, Westbrook seems to be inbounding the ball more often. An interesting look after Brook’s preference of having a lanky shooting guard take on this responsibility almost exclusively.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Adams had trouble chasing down shooters on the perimeter when going up against the small ball lineups Houston kept rolling out. The tradeoff for offensive rebounds and inside presence seemed to be the way to go, however, at least in the first half.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ibaka has always fought for rebounds with is own teammates. Kanter is even worse at it. So when both are going after a rebound there’s a fairly high likelihood it’s going to end up in the hands of the other team.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eyeball-test&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emotional and sloppy.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve used the word sloppy here too much for having only played 4 games. These turnovers have to stop. 24 is too many to have a comfortable chance winning any game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-03-2015/okc-hou-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-03-2015/okc-hou-notes</guid>
        
        
        <category>hou</category>
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Game Recap: Thunder vs. Rockets</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;okc-105---hou-110&quot;&gt;OKC 105 - HOU 110&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oklahoma City head coach Billy Donovan experienced another milestone on his NBA journey tonight – his first loss as an NBA coach. The Thunder were muffled this evening and allowed James Harden to have his first break out game of the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Oklahoma City Thunder started slowly tonight. The first few minutes of the game were hectic, up and down the court basketball that featured several turnovers for both teams. After throwing the ball around loosely the Thunder finally settled in and took the lead. James Harden looked timid in the first quarter, waiting until there was just 6:31 left in the quarter to take his first shot of the game despite having open looks. Harden went on a quick scoring spurt though and hit several shots in the first quarter. The Thunder won the quarter by 5 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second quarter looked like it was going to be more of the same. The Thunder looked comfortable and in control of the game en route to pushing the lead to 10+ points. They took an 11-point lead into halftime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third quarter was not friendly to the Thunder. Russell Westbrook was limited in third quarter action after finding himself in foul trouble. He picked up 3 personal fouls in the quarter. The offense hit a roadblock and only scored 14 points in the quarter while Houston put up 28 and took the lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facing losing for the first time, Russell Westbrook came out firing in the fourth quarter. He played all 12 minutes to close out the game going 5-8 and putting up 12 points in the quarter. It wasn’t enough, however, and Houston held on to win the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Harden finished with 37 points it took him a lot of shots to get there. He shot just 12-26 from the floor and 4-12 from the 3 point line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Durant had another good outing, scoring 29 points on 9-19 from the floor and 4-9 from deep. Russell Westbrook chipped in 25 on 10-16 shooting, and 3-6 from the arc. He nearly had a triple-double though, which is becoming a nightly threat, by dishing out 11 assists and pulling down 8 rebounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serge Ibaka had a bit of a disappointing game. He put up a double-double as well (12p, 11r), but he shot poorly and failed to assert himself early in the game when the Rockets began the game with James Harden guarding the Thunder big man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that hurt the Thunder the most in this game was turnovers. It’s something they have struggled with early in the season. The Thunder gave up 19 turnovers against the Spurs, 20 against the Magic, and finally seemed to limit TOs against the Nuggets giving up just 13 turnovers. Tonight against the Rockets the Thunder gave up 27 turnovers. No matter how bad the competition, if you give them 24 extra chances then the game becomes very difficult. The Rockets scored 21 points off of those 24 turnovers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder showed that the offense still has great potential – they shot better than the Rockets – but they have to treasure the ball more. It’s unfortunate that the first Thunder loss of the season was to the struggling Rockets, but it had to come at some point. A loss on the second night of a back to back on the road is not a terrible loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This team is fun to watch and they will be all season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up next: Thunder vs. Toronto Raptors in OKC at 7 p.m. CST.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 23:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-02-2015/game-recap-rockets1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-02-2015/game-recap-rockets1</guid>
        
        
        <category>recap</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
