<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thunder Op-Ed</title>
    <description>Welcome to Thunder Op-Ed! Come back often or follow us on twitter  for content, thoughts, and ramblings on your Oklahoma City Thunder. This site is independent of the OKC Thunder organization and all views expressed are that of the author.
</description>
    <link>http://thunderoped.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thunderoped.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 03:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 03:49:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thunder Weekly Forecast</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;games&quot;&gt;Games&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monday-november-30-2015-at-700-pm-cst---at-atlanta-hawks&quot;&gt;Monday, November 30, 2015, at 7:00 PM CST - at Atlanta Hawks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another game against a former key Thunder player. Thabo Sefolosha is playing about 23 minutes per game for the Hawks and turning in a solid season. Serge Ibaka will have his hands full going up against Paul Milsap who is averaging a near double-double 19 games into the season. Milsap is putting up 18.2 points per game and pulling down 9.5 rebounds per game. This game will be shown on FS Oklahoma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thursday-december-3-2015-at-600-pm-cst---at-miami-heat&quot;&gt;Thursday, December 3, 2015, at 6:00 PM CST - at Miami Heat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rosters are significantly different but the wounds still run deep for Oklahoma City fans. Any game against the Miami Heat brings back cringe inducing feelings. Lebron James has moved on to Cleveland, but Dwyane Wade and Chris Bosh remain from the 2012 team that defeated the Thunder in the NBA Finals. Bosh is bordering on averaging a double-double by scoring 17.5 points per game and cleaning the class for an even 9 rebounds per game. Wade is beginning to show his age, yet still remains dangerous. He is scoring 17.1 points per game (would be his second lowest average of his career) and has seen his rebounds and assists per game decline over the last four seasons. This game will be televised on TNT and FS Oklahoma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;three-things-to-watch-for&quot;&gt;Three Things to Watch for:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;road-struggles&quot;&gt;Road Struggles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Oklahoma City Thunder are only 3-3 this season in road games. The Thunder have one of the greatest home fan bases in the NBA, but true contenders must win on the road. This would be a good week to begin winning road games. The games are spread apart and there is not a lot of distance between Atlanta and Miami.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;serge-ibaka&quot;&gt;Serge Ibaka&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ibaka struggled in two back to back games earlier this month against the New York Knicks and New Orleans Pelicans. In those games he only scored 8 and 6 points respectively, while shooting 4-13 and 2-11. Since that New York game on November 20th, the Thunder big man has scored in double digits in 4 consecutive games. In those four games he’s averaging 13.25 ppg, 6.25 rpg, and 2.75 blocks per game. In this short burst he is shooting 57.1% from the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;russell-westbrook&quot;&gt;Russell Westbrook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westbrook has only scored fewer than 20 points in two games this season. One of those games was Friday against Detroit. The other was against the Denver Nuggets – a game in which Westbrook played just 25 minutes. Following the Denver game, Westbrook bounced back against the Houston Rockets and scored 25 points, dished 11 assists, pulled down 8 rebounds. He did this on 10-16 shooting from the floor and 3-6 from deep. Westbrook should have another solid follow up game against Jeff Teague and the Hawks on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;around-the-leage&quot;&gt;Around the Leage:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some games that could be fun to watch around the NBA this week&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tuesday-december-1-2015-6-pm-cst--los-angeles-lakers--philadephia-76ers&quot;&gt;Tuesday, December 1, 2015 (6 PM CST) – Los Angeles Lakers @ Philadephia 76ers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not going to be a great display of NBA basketball, but it will feature Kobe Bryant’s shell and some good young big men in Julius Randle, Nerlens Noel, and Jahlil Okafor. But most important to this game is that it might be Philadelphia’s last serious chance to end their notorious losing streak. This game can only be seen locally in the respective markets or on NBA League Pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thursday-december-3-2015-830-pm-cst---san-antonio-spurs--memphis-grizzlies&quot;&gt;Thursday, December 3, 2015 (8:30 PM CST) - San Antonio Spurs @ Memphis Grizzlies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rematch of the 2013 Western Conference Finals could be interesting. Memphis is 6-4 in their last 10 games and seem to be gradually figuring things out. The Spurs are, well, the Spurs. They’re sitting at 14-3. This game will be shown on TNT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;saturday-december-5-2015-6-pm-cst---cleveland-cavaliers--miami-heat&quot;&gt;Saturday, December 5, 2015 (6 PM CST) - Cleveland Cavaliers @ Miami Heat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleveland Cavaliers @ Miami Heat – Lebron James makes another return to Miami to play against old friends Chris Bosh and Dwyane Wade. This game will be shown on NBA TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;by-the-numbers&quot;&gt;By the Numbers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;115.3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder are averaging 115.3 points per game on the road this season. This is higher than the season long average of 109.4 points per game. However, they are giving up 110.3 points per game compared to the season average of 102.8 points per game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-1&quot;&gt;13&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder have scored 100 points or more in 13 games this season. Only Golden State (18) has more such games. Atlanta has only surpassed 100 points 9 times this season. Miami has only scored 100 in 3 games so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-2&quot;&gt;47.7&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of rebounds on average that the Thunder pull down per game. This is the best rate in the NBA. Miami ranks 10th with 45.2 rebounds per game, and Atlanta ranks lowly at 28th pulling down just 41.2 boards per game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever and always, Thunder Up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-29-2015/Weekly-Forecast</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-29-2015/Weekly-Forecast</guid>
        
        
        <category>forecast</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Week in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;scores&quot;&gt;Scores&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-117---114-dallas&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City 117 - 114 Dallas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a solid win for the Oklahoma City Thunder. In the, hopefully final, game before Kevin Durant’s return, the Thunder knocked off the Dallas Mavericks. It was another Sunset Sunday. The Thunder moved to 3-1 on Sunset Sundays at the Chesapeake Energy Arena. Russell Westbrook had his customary double-double on 31 points and 11 assists. He also had 5 steals and 5 rebounds. The Thunder also got solid performances out of Serge Ibaka, Dion Waiters, Nick Collison, and Anthony Morrow. Perhaps the biggest shift for the rest of the season came with the emergence of Anthony Morrow. Head Coach Billy Donovan was forced into playing the 3-point specialist due to Kevin Durant’s injury and Morrow finally made the most of the opportunity. He finished with 14 points on 5-9 shooting (2-3 from long distance) in 24 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-111---89-utah&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City 111 - 89 Utah&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Durant made his return from the hamstring injury in this road game, which was the second game of a back-to-back. He showed that he can pick up right where we expected him too. The former MVP and four time scoring champion finished with 27 points on a ridiculously efficient 10-13 shooting (3-6 from distance) while also pulling down 6 rebounds, swiping 4 steals, and blocking one shot. Anthony Morrow again seized his opportunity finishing with 15 points on 6-8 shooting (3-4 from distance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;oklahoma-city-110---99-brooklyn&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City 110 - 99 Brooklyn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the Kevin Durant’s return to the Chesapeake Energy Arena after his hamstring injury. He did not disappoint. Durant had another efficient night scoring 30 points on 11-18 shooting (5-8 from distance). He grabbed 6 rebounds and dished out 5 assists as well. Russell Westbrook pitched in another double-double scoring 27 points on 10-16 shooting while dropping 13 dimes. Dion Waiters had another solid performance tonight scoring 16 points on 6-13 shooting. Anthony Morrow had a down game with just 6 points on 2-5 shooting. Serge Ibaka hopefully had a game that can get him going on the season. He finished with 12 points on an efficient 4-9 shooting. Ibaka made all of his free throws (4-4) and pulled down 8 boards as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;overall-thoughts&quot;&gt;Overall Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a really good week for the Thunder. Kevin Durant returned from his injury, which hopefully will not linger. The team picked up three wins: one against a good team, one against a mediocre team, and one against a bad team. All three count the same in the win column though. The Dallas win was the most impressive of the week. The Mavericks are the best team Oklahoma City played this week and they were streaking. The Thunder ended the Mavericks’ six game win streak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibly the most interesting thing to happen this week, outside of the Thunder having a full starting line-up again, is the return of Anthony Morrow to the rotation. He played an average of just over 22 minutes per game this week and seemed to relish the opportunity and thrive in the positions in which he was put.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;up-next&quot;&gt;Up Next&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder take on the Detroit Pistons on Friday, November 27, at the Chesapeake Energy Arena. Reggie Jackson will be back in town. Then The Thunder take on the Atlanta Hawks on Monday, November 30, in Atlanta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever and always, Thunder Up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 09:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-26-2015/This-Week-In-Review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-26-2015/This-Week-In-Review</guid>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eyeball Test: Mavericks @ Thunder</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;dal-114---okc-117&quot;&gt;DAL 114 - OKC 117&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder showed some grit after giving up a 10 point lead in a 20 point swing for Dallas, but came back and held on to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;From the tip, the Thunder finally looked like a team again. Defense still a struggle, which is confusing, but it looks like they’re trying again.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Waiters lost the ability to hit a layup about two games ago. Don’t know where that went.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The rotation for this game may have been Donovan’s most reasonable to date. Instead of trying to get struggling guys going, this team needed to get going as a whole so Morrow and Collison saw meaningful minutes and helped the Thunder win.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Singler does try. Sometimes too hard, and control is a definite skill. Two fouls on the same possession is not helpful, and when he catches the ball on the perimeter it’s not going down. He tries, but he’s got to get better before giving him significant minutes makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Payne? Interesting, but good to see. Knocks down a midrange with confidence. Had some rookie mistakes and two mishaps with Ibaka on fast breaks, but I like the potential and the fact that he’s getting meaningful minutes here and there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Speaking of confidence, Ibaka looking better. Throughout the game it came and went, and he still seems a step off on defense. His confidence looked better though. His block on Deron Williams to help seal the win was vintage Ibaka, but prior to that he was making some silly fouls. His one on one defense mostly held up, however, so hopefully Ibaka keeps trending in a positive direction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kanter commanded a double team, and instead of trying to power through he passed out to an open Morrow for an easy catch and shoot three. Great to see.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Deron Williams had a surprising amount of space throughout the game when guarded by Westbrook. He even blew by Westbrook on one drive. Westbrook locked in a lot more toward the end of the game and looked like he was trying throughout, but in the pick and roll Deron was getting easy looks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Did Williams really trip himself and get awarded a clear path foul? Yeah, that just happened.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One thing the Thunder has to get over is the collapse that happens every game. In the 3rd quarter, after a 8-0 Dallas run, the Thunder were all of a sudden down 10 and having to dig themselves out of a hole.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The officials couldn’t make up their minds during the game. They went from calling everything, to calling nothing. I understand each game will be called differently, but having no consistency in what is getting called is ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the defense picks up the scoreboard goes in the right direction. By the end of the 3rd the Thunder had pulled out of their hole to have a 2 point lead heading into the 4th.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Morrow hitting nice floaters in the paint. Great to see him get going.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is it with this team and not following plays down the court? Waiters chased down Wes Matthews, causing him to miss what would have been easy fast break points. The Mavs still got an easy two points though, because no other Thunder players followed the play. All four were still on the other side of the half court line.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The adjustment period for this team seems so slow. It took several straight losses for them to start hitting a stride originally. Then when Durant went down the wheels fell off the bus, and it took 5 more games for the Thunder to look like a team again. The defense still has to get better, but it’s a step in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eyeball-test&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In sync.&lt;/strong&gt; They still collapsed, but they came back and played some good defense late to seal a win against a surprisingly decent Dallas team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 19:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-23-2015/dal-okc-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-23-2015/dal-okc-notes</guid>
        
        
        <category>dal</category>
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thunder Weekly Forecast</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;games&quot;&gt;Games&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monday-november-23-at-800-pm-cst--at-utah-jazz&quot;&gt;Monday, November 23 at 8:00 PM CST – at Utah Jazz&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder will open the week on the second night of a back-to-back against Utah, yet another tough Western Conference foe. Utah doesn’t have the most powerful offense, but their elite defense is allowing the second lowest point total in the league. This will be a difficult road game for Oklahoma City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wednesday-november-25-at-700-pm-cst--vs-brooklyn-nets&quot;&gt;Wednesday, November 25 at 7:00 PM CST – vs. Brooklyn Nets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Nets are off to a horrendous start this season. They’re just 3-11, which ties them for the third worst record in all of the NBA. They still have some talent in guys like Joe Johnson, Brook Lopez and Thaddeus Young, but they haven’t been playing very well. The Thunder should be able to take this game easily, especially at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;friday-november-27-at-700-pm-cst--vs-detroit-pistons&quot;&gt;Friday, November 27 at 7:00 PM CST – vs. Detroit Pistons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has been looking forward to this game since last year’s trade deadline: the day Reggie Jackson returns to OKC. Jackson didn’t depart on great terms, and Thunder fans would love to see Russell Westbrook dominate against the young talented point guard. Detroit has a solid squad behind coach Stan Van Gundy, so the Thunder will have to play well to knock off Jackson’s new team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;three-things-to-watch-for&quot;&gt;Three Things to Watch for:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;billy-donovan&quot;&gt;Billy Donovan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re coming up on a month into Donovan’s first season as an NBA head coach, and he has yet to wow anyone. To say he’s been bad or a downgrade from Scott Brooks is unfair, but he seems to be struggling in some ways. His rotations have been somewhat questionable, and it kind of seems that he’s struggling to keep his guys motivated. Here’s hoping that the team can get it together behind Donovan, sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anthony-morrow&quot;&gt;Anthony Morrow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morrow has struggled so far this season, which has come as a surprise to everyone following his great season last year. He had a great game Sunday against Dallas though, shooting the ball well and tallying a season high 14 points. It will be interesting to see if he can build off this performance and solidify his role on the team again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;westbrooks-turnovers&quot;&gt;Westbrook’s Turnovers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westbrook is averaging over five turnovers per game this year, and he’s had six games with six turnovers or more. He’s always going to turn the ball over some with his style of play, but he really needs to keep his average under five, and even under four if possible. Turnovers have always been a weakness of his, but at this rate he is on pace for his worst season in that category. Hopefully he can start to take care of the basketball more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;around-the-league&quot;&gt;Around the League:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some games around the NBA to watch for this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;los-angeles-lakers-at-golden-state-warriors--tuesday-november-24-at-930-pm-cst&quot;&gt;Los Angeles Lakers at Golden State Warriors – Tuesday, November 24 at 9:30 PM CST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this matchup looks like it will be a blowout in favor of the defending champion Warriors, it carries a pretty big historical significance. The Warriors are 15-0 to begin this week, and just one more victory will give them the best start for a team in NBA history. They should be able to come out on top against a bad Lakers team, but it’s always great to see history in the making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cleveland-cavaliers-at-toronto-raptors----wednesday-november-25-at-630-pm-cst&quot;&gt;Cleveland Cavaliers at Toronto Raptors  - Wednesday, November 25 at 6:30 PM CST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game will feature two of the top Eastern Conference teams, and features more than a handful of talented players. Guys like DeMar DeRozan and Kyle Lowry will look to lead the Raptors over LeBron James, Kevin Love and a very deep Cavaliers team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dallas-mavericks-at-san-antonio-spurs--wednesday-november-25-at-730-pm-cst&quot;&gt;Dallas Mavericks at San Antonio Spurs – Wednesday, November 25 at 7:30 PM CST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mavericks are much better than everyone expected them to be, and the Spurs are as dangerous as always. Combine that with the fact that this is one of the better rivalries in the Western Conference, and you’ve got a recipe for a great basketball game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;by-the-numbers&quot;&gt;By the Numbers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wins for the Thunder so far on second nights of a back-to-back, out of three tries. They will look to change that against Utah on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-1&quot;&gt;4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consecutive 30 plus point performances for Westbrook. He’s averaging 37 points per game in that stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-2&quot;&gt;8.8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder’s positive rebound differential so far this season, which makes them the league leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-23-2015/weekly-forecast</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-23-2015/weekly-forecast</guid>
        
        
        <category>forecast</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eyeball Test Roundup: New York, Memphis, Boston, Philadephia</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;nyk-93---okc-90&quot;&gt;NYK 93 - OKC 90&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shots wouldn’t fall, but the Thunder didn’t make any real attempt to try for better ones as they fell to a weirdly effective Knicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I was at the game against the Pelicans, so I want to make this note: Roberson was fantastic. Such a major plus for this team. He is making his shots with a lot more confidence, and he is becoming effective on both ends. He’ll never be a world-beater on offense, but he’s getting much better.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Roberson made a comment postgame about how this defense has the bigs dropping back and puts more pressure on the guards. It’s been discussed before, but hearing it from Roberson just reminded me how much better the bigs are than the guards for the Thunder. Roberson is the only consistently good defender, with Westbrook and Waiters helping when they want to. With the front court rotation, Adams, Ibaka, Collison, and usually Durant can be counted on to give solid defensive minutes. Why would the defensive schemes focus on the effort and reliability of the guards, when that clearly is the defensive weakness of the team? It could possibly serve Monty Williams well to rethink what this team is capable of, and who is capable of it. Maybe his optimism will pay off. Hopefully.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Another note from the Pelicans game that carried over into this night. The jogging back down the court has to stop. Kanter and Waiters are frequently late getting back on offense (unless there’s a fastbreak opportunity). It slows down the pace uneccesarily, and when Waiters especially picks up his intensity simply by running back and being engaged you can see the obvious impact it has.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Singler can’t shoot. It’s not happening. He is however improving elsewhere. His fouling has decreased ever so slightly, and his activity keeps plays alive.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This season every good thing this team does has to have an asterisk next to it that says something along the lines of ‘when engaged’ or ‘on occasion’. The inconsistency has killed this team. It’s been the only consistent thing they have, other than Westbrook’s nightly box numbers. When the Thunder are executing well you can see what Donovan has brought tactically, and that potential is exciting. What’s very troubling, however, is that the effort just isn’t there. Brooks had his struggles, and he isn’t in OKC anymore because of them, but one (underrated) thing he brought to this team was motivation. They always fought, and it put them in the hunt in so many situations they had no business being in.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ibaka is struggling. He seems lost and lacking all his confidence. He’s routinely getting great looks in the pick-and-roll with Westbrook, but even those shots he’s failing to hit. His robotic consistency that has served this team so well in years passed is missing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t be fooled by the low score of this game. It wasn’t because the Thunder were effective defensively, it was because so many possessions ran down the clock. Less possessions means less points.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eyeball-test&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unmotivated.&lt;/strong&gt; Donovan can coach, but can he motivate? And how does a bench also consisting of Monty Williams and Mo Cheeks not have the ability to push this team? It’s early, but it’s starting to feel like something may be amiss with this team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;okc-114---mem-122&quot;&gt;OKC 114 - MEM 122&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roberson was out with the flu, and accordingly the Memphis guards lit up the Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Memphis looked ready to go out of the gate, ripping the ball straight from Thunder players’ hands on two consecutive possessions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;No Roberson, which looked worse than some people would say it sounds. Singler had to start, and with his fouling tendencies was forced to sit early. The team was down two wing players, including their best wing defender, and new Grizzly Mario Chalmers along with Mike Conley made them pay. It seemed to start when Cameron Payne saw his first meaningful minutes, and was baited into several dumb fouls by Chalmers. Payne was recovering and contesting well, however, which bodes well for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Chalmers continued to bulldoze his way to the line after Payne was moved onto Courtney Lee. Augustin didn’t make the same rookie mistakes, but physically he was completely outmatched against the bigger, stronger Chalmers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The interior defense from the Thunder gave them a chance. Adams made Gasol work all game. Both were in foul trouble by the end, but Adams stood his ground the entire night. Ibaka looked better against Zach Randolph than he ever has in the past, as well. The only shots that came consistently for the Grizzlies’ bigs were long, midrange twos. The problem is those two have that range, but it severely limited their potential potency.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Similarly on the offensive end, nothing was coming easy on the interior. The Thunder’s guards continued to drive inside, which often resulted in getting stuffed and/or turning the ball over. The Thunder couldn’t hold on to the ball all night, with bobbled passes and just losing the ball on their own, and so very few good kickouts resulted in Thunder points.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The bigs also had their work cut out for them on the offensive boards. Adams was sent to the line multiple times (one of the reasons Gasol was in foul trouble), and he continued to look much improved at the line. If this continues to be a thing, Adams’ ability to shoot free throws could allow for some good late-game defensive lineups without the liability of having a poor foul shooter on the court.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Roberson was missed for his defense, but his replacement (Singler) couldn’t hit any wide open threes which made Roberson missed for his offense as well. When you’d rather see Roberson take a three-point shot, it means something is seriously wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Westbrook takes over, it’s fascinating to watch. It’s not ideal and it usually means he’s given up on his teammates, but it’s still enthralling to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who thought Chalmers was going to win a game for the Grizz?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Thunder finally looked locked in for the final 3 minutes. Where was this intensity and focus for the first part of the fourth quarter, let alone the entire game? Westbrook was hitting anything he wanted, but the Grizzlies’ guards kept answering to keep them in the lead.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eyeball-test-1&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out of sync.&lt;/strong&gt; They were missing two starters, but there’s enough talent on this team. It’s not an excuse for the issues the Thunder can’t seem to escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;bos-100---okc-85&quot;&gt;BOS 100 - OKC 85&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A complete fourth quarter collapse spelled doom against a well coached, consistent Boston team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Great defense to start. Morrow and Westbrook both working hard to get over screens, which isn’t necessarily the norm.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Terrible shot selection of long twos and quick threes led to easy offense for Boston. Westbrook was trying to shoot Boston out of the game, and seemed to lose control. Donovan sat him a few minutes earlier than he usually does, and it was a much needed break.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I could watch Kelly Olynyk try to guard Enes Kanter all night. Way too easy to score.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I like the look of Collison next to Kanter. His passing compliments Kanter’s post play, and his defense can help hide Kanter.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Westbrook reigned it in the 2nd quarter, but he’s still on the edge of being completely out of control.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Boston’s offense executes so well. The Thunder tried to make the game sloppier to break it down, which worked for a little while. They just haven’t asserted themselves in terms of size or pace all season, instead simply matching what the other team is trying to run.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ibaka much more consistent. He was hitting his shots and was where he needed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Roberson starting to shoot without hesitation. Making it at this point is a bonus, because what’s really huge is the improved confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Brad Stevens has this team working so well for what they have talent-wise. They kept their cool all game to come back slowly but surely.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Westbrook against the world only works when Westbrook can shoot. When you’re 5-20 maybe it’s time to attempt to trust a teammate or two.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Complete offensive collapse beginning in the late 3rd quarter and continuing throughout the 4th. Just 11 points to close out a game is embarrassing. Kanter and Waiters didn’t bring the necessary spark to offset the missing contribution from Durant, and despite Ibaka’s great night, the same problems persisted with this team.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eyeball-test-2&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Off. And short handed.&lt;/strong&gt; It was hard against the 76ers to really get an idea of how much Durant would be missed, but the well-coached Celtics made it painfully obvious. This could be a great learning experience of where some big flaws exist, but the Thunder as a whole seem really off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;phi-85---okc-102&quot;&gt;PHI 85 - OKC 102&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A close game ended easily as the Sixers seemed to run out of gas, giving the Thunder a pass despite offensive struggles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Morrow got the first start for a missing Durant. With how much Donovan is pushing Singler it was an interesting, albeit hopeful, choice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;With the start Morrow also got his rhythm back, making 4 consecutive shots after missing his first. Got to get him better looks when Durant comes back and Morrow goes back to the bench.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Adams putting in ridiculous effort to make Jahlil Okafor struggle. He was shut down all night, and you could tell it was a major focus for the Thunder. This season it hasn’t been opposing bigs that have given this team fits. Something to watch going forward is how the Thunder guards react to getting roasted on a nightly basis.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Okafor didn’t look as bad on defense as advertised, and meanwhile Nerlens Noel was tearing it up on offense. Kinda sad they will waste away in Philly, at least for a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Singler seems to be improving game to game, ever so slightly. Not his shooting though, which is still terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Collison is so good at being in exactly the right spot. He makes mistakes, but not nearly as many as most players. He’s getting older and less effective, but when it comes to stability he’s still very useful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Westbrook with his 2nd triple double in a row. Here we go. Russell against the world.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;D.J. Augustin had some great plays in the 4th quarter. He’s failed to live up to the impressive play the first few games of the season, but it’s good to see it come back at times.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The 76ers faded at the end of the game to relinquish what had been a fairly close game to the Thunder for an easy win.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eyeball-test-3&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lacking.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s Philadelphia, so a win was almost guaranteed. The Thunder are going to have to bring a lot more to the table to keep up with more talented teams while Durant warms the bench in a suit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-22-2015/nyk-mem-bos-phi-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-22-2015/nyk-mem-bos-phi-notes</guid>
        
        
        <category>nyk</category>
        
        <category>mem</category>
        
        <category>bos</category>
        
        <category>phi</category>
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thunder Weekly Forecast</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;games&quot;&gt;Games&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monday-november-16-at-700-pm-cst--at-memphis-grizzlies&quot;&gt;Monday, November 16 at 7:00 PM CST – at Memphis Grizzlies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder will open the week with a tough one in Memphis. The Grizzlies have had a slow start this year, but they’re always a tough matchup for Oklahoma City. Having faced one another three times in the playoffs so far, these two teams have developed quite a rivalry that is always fun to watch. Russell Westbrook and co. will look to knock off Memphis in their lone road game this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wednesday-november-18-at-700-pm-cst--vs-new-orleans-pelicans&quot;&gt;Wednesday, November 18 at 7:00 PM CST – vs. New Orleans Pelicans&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This matchup provided a thriller four times last season, with New Orleans coming out on top in three of those games. The Pelicans are battling an injury-riddled season so far, but they’re still a very talented team lead by All Star Anthony Davis. Look for this to be another exciting game, and hopefully we won’t have to witness any Davis magic this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;friday-november-20-at-700-pm-cst--vs-new-york-knicks&quot;&gt;Friday, November 20 at 7:00 PM CST – vs. New York Knicks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Knicks are just 5-6 so far this season, but they have a pretty solid team behind perennial All Star Carmelo Anthony and exciting rookie Kristaps Porzingis. That being said, this should still be a game the Thunder can take care of at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sunday-november-22-at-600-pm-cst--vs-dallas-mavericks&quot;&gt;Sunday, November 22 at 6:00 PM CST – vs. Dallas Mavericks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mavericks were not expected to make much noise this season after losing out on the DeAndre Jordan sweepstakes, but they have surprised so far, going 6-4. This is one of the Thunder’s biggest rivalries, and whether Dallas is great or average, these games are almost always tough wins. Hopefully OKC can net a win on their home court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;three-things-to-watch-for&quot;&gt;Three Things to Watch for:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;offense-without-kevin-durant&quot;&gt;Offense without Kevin Durant&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Durant’s hamstring injury has not been labeled as very serious, but the Thunder is going to be very careful and not rush him back. In his absence, the Thunder offense is going to have to step up. Obviously a lot of that burden falls on Westbrook’s shoulders, but the Thunder will need Serge Ibaka, Dion Waiters, Enes Kanter and Anthony Morrow to especially step up and help cover that 25 to 30 points the team will be missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;big-man-defense&quot;&gt;Big Man Defense&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder’s schedule this week includes Marc Gasol, Zach Randolph, Davis, Dirk Nowitzki, and, though it’s probably early to include him on this list, Porzingis. That’s a lot of scoring potential from opposing bigs, and Ibaka, Kanter, Steven Adams, Nick Collison and Mitch McGary will certainly have their work cut out defensively. It will be especially interesting to see how Kanter plays on defense, an area in which he is known to struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anthony-morrow-vs-kyle-singler&quot;&gt;Anthony Morrow vs. Kyle Singler&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these guys have struggled so far, but history tells us that Morrow is a much better option. For some puzzling reason that may be based on defense, Singler has gotten to play a lot of minutes that we would’ve expected Morrow to get. It seems that Morrow is now out of sync when he does get to play, and Singler makes dumb mistakes and shoots poorly too. Billy Donovan is going to have to figure out what to do with these guys soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;around-the-league&quot;&gt;Around the League:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some games around the NBA to watch for this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;indiana-pacers-at-chicago-bulls--monday-november-16-at-700-pm-cst&quot;&gt;Indiana Pacers at Chicago Bulls – Monday, November 16 at 7:00 PM CST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This matchup between two of the Eastern Conference’s top teams should be a good one. The Bulls have some great talent in guys like Jimmy Butler, Derrick Rose and Pau Gasol, and the Pacers feature the likes of Monta Ellis and Paul George, the latter of which is quietly having a great season so far. This one should be fun to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;milwaukee-bucks-at-cleveland-cavaliers--thursday-november-19-at-700-pm-cst&quot;&gt;Milwaukee Bucks at Cleveland Cavaliers – Thursday, November 19 at 7:00 PM CST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bucks are just 5-5, but they’re also only one of two teams to defeat the Cavaliers so far. That game happened last week, and turned out to be a double overtime thriller. Hopefully the rematch proves to be another great game between these two Eastern Conference teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;golden-state-warriors-at-los-angeles-clippers--thursday-november-19-at-930-pm-cst&quot;&gt;Golden State Warriors at Los Angeles Clippers – Thursday, November 19 at 9:30 PM CST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This matchup is always fun to watch, whether it falls in the playoffs or regular season. The Warriors begin the week as the lone undefeated team in the league, and the Clippers start hasn’t been too shabby either. This primetime matchup should prove to be as entertaining as always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;by-the-numbers&quot;&gt;By the Numbers:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;31.8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Points per game for Anthony Davis against the Thunder last year. He also shot about 59 percent in his dominant performances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-1&quot;&gt;25.4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Points per game for Westbrook in his career against the Knicks. It’s the most he’s averaged against any team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-2&quot;&gt;38&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number of games OKC has played against Memphis since the start of the 2010-11 season. The Thunder is 18-20 in those games.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-16-2015/weekly-forecast</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-16-2015/weekly-forecast</guid>
        
        
        <category>forecast</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Game Recap: Thunder vs. 76ers</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;okc---phi-85&quot;&gt;102 OKC - PHI 85&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight the Oklahoma City Thunder beat the Philadelphia 76ers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our hearts remain with Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-11-13/0.jpg&quot; title=&quot;French Flag (Source - Trey Shelton)&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:500px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 22:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-13-2015/game-recap-sixers1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-13-2015/game-recap-sixers1</guid>
        
        
        <category>phi</category>
        
        <category>recap</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eyeball Test: Thunder @ Wizards</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;okc-125---was-101&quot;&gt;OKC 125 - WAS 101&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder build on their good habits and blow out the Wizards to fend off the national media drooling over a Durant homecoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Great start again. This looks like a thing now. No matter the end result, the Thunder have consistently started very strong.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The got a little too comfortable and the risky passes/turnovers came back out. They got back on track pretty quickly though.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ibaka hit a mice running floater off the dribble. It looks very much under control, a vast improvement over the robotic-like attempts we’ve seen in past seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Roberson knocking down threes. The whole team shot ridiculously efficient from deep against Washington, but Roberson looks more confident in his shot in general.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Westbrook didn’t score until there were 5 minutes left in the first quarter. Instead he was lasering in passes from the top of the key to Durant standing by himself under the basket.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Durant is typically terrible in DC. His visit home with family and friends seems to distract him, although that’s completely speculation. This visit, however, with all the media attention and the Thunder (and Durant) working back into form he was locked in.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;McGary in the early bench rotation again. Great energy to start and had some good chemistry alongside D.J. Augustin.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Singler looked like he was having a more successful game, but it doesn’t change one thing: When he touches the ball, no matter where it is on the floor, it seems to bring the same results as Kevin Martin catching the ball in the corner several seasons ago. They both were likely to end in a turnover.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The bench, when Waiters isn’t being dominant, seems to lack a confidence it’s had since James Harden was drafted. The Thunder have always had an explosive ball handler coming off the bench that had the ability to drive, dish, and hit big shots. Harden is now in Houston of course, and Reggie Jackson is tearing it up in Detroit next to Andre Drummond. As the game progressed and Waiters was hitting his stride, the bench started to click. He’s making positive progress each game, and while his shooting percentages may not be sustainable, having ‘Contract Dion’ keep it up will be huge for the Thunder. Also, #contractdion looks weirdly similar to ‘contradiction’. Coincidences?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Adams was unlucky with the whistles, sitting early due to foul trouble twice during the game. It flipped the center rotation, putting Kanter with the starters and Adams with the bench. And he ate the Washington backup bigs. He was rebounding, or causing havoc underneath, it seemed like every play. Rebounding advantage with Adams and Kanter is a very good thing, and hopefully KD can come back and maintain his progress back to rebounding like he used to. He had 10 in the first half against Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I was worried about Ibaka’s defensive quickness last game. It’s still lingering, but when he’s on he looks just as good as he used to. Here’s hoping it’s just a spotty start to the season that will pick up to where his offense has been so far.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve alluded to it a few times, but Durant’s hamstring strain puts him out at least a week. Luckily there’s a two day break and a light schedule coming up, but an injured Durant is never good. He played after the obvious funny landing that hobbled him up, and he said it just felt sore after the game. Hopefully it doesn’t slow down his rounding into form very much. He was making huge strides up to this point.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Westbrook is one assist away from a triple double he has a one-track mind. He’s going to hit his teammates with passes until one of them makes a shot. It was getting later in the third quarter, and he knew he wouldn’t be playing in the fourth with the 20+ point blowout going strong. It took three empty trips down the court until someone could hit a shot. Westbrook then resumed scoring at will.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It would have been really nice to see the Thunder against a healthy Wizards team, but 97 points in three quarters means something is going right.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I get sad when Morrow misses 3-pointers. He also struggled defensively, but so did everyone in the fourth quarter. Because blowout.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;With such a huge lead I’m surprised there was no Cameron Payne sighting until 3:22 left in the game. He scored his first career points with a nifty driving scoop shot. He’s active on defense, but he’s not the strongest right now and has some definite work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eyeball-test&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t have much to say here. They blew out an injury riddled team that’s been the center of a building media frenzy trying to steal away the Thunder’s face. Westbrook did his thing, and Dion grew bigger in his sixth man role. Hopefully the Thunder can hold off teams this next week and Durant comes back healthy and ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 19:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-11-2015/okc-was-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-11-2015/okc-was-notes</guid>
        
        
        <category>was</category>
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>KD visits DC</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everybody in the world knows that Kevin Durant is going to be a free agent this summer. The NBA knows it. NBA fans know it. Oklahoma City knows it. Yet, the continual media fascination with his impending free agency is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Durant recently said that the Washington Wizards fans openly recruiting him during games when Oklahoma City - his current team, don’t forget - travels to the east coast. Yes, Durant is from DC and he loves his home town. Yes, he can choose to play anywhere in the world he wants next season. The media is so dead set on Durant being Lebron James and returning home that they can’t get out of their own way when discussing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today on PTI, Tony Kornheiser and Michael Wilbon addressed Durant’s homegoing. Two days after he said the Wizards fans were being disrespectful to their own team by openly lobbying another player to come to the city &lt;strong&gt;a year from now&lt;/strong&gt;, Wilbon stated that he wasn’t sure what Durant was doing. A man who always discusses his unfettered access to the biggest and best players in the NBA said that he couldn’t tell which way Durant was leaning. Did that stop him from giving his thoughts anyway? No. He did say, however, that Durant keeping DC at arm’s length may be an attempt to lessen the blow if he decides not to return home. He said it’s difficult to go home. Yes. Yes it is. Not everybody is Lebron James. What he failed to mention was that Kevin Durant is still playing in Oklahoma City. Maybe he was doing it because he actually likes this little part of the Mid-Southwest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kornheiser went on to say that Durant should re-sign for one year in Oklahoma City and then leave for the Los Angeles Lakers with Russell Westbrook during the summer of 2017. The one year contract, no matter what the long term results may become, is a sentiment others such as Zach Lowe have also expressed as Durant’s best move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody is giving Oklahoma City a chance. Yes - we are a small market. We are not LA, DC, or New York. We never will be. We don’t want to be, and today’s NBA has a global reach that has allowed OKC’s biggest stars to sign some of the most lucrative endorsement deals internationally. We don’t have the big fancy nightclubs, with celebrities and paparazzi. But what we do have is a loyal fanbase. This city supported a 1-12 team in its first year and has not looked back since. We know how lucky we are to have Durant and Westbrook. Sure, if you want to play in a city of 10+ million people, this isn’t your place. But if you want to play in front of a great fanbase who will show up every single night, filling the arena with a defeaning roar, then this is your place. If you want to be showered with constant praise, this is your place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever and always, Thunder Up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-10-2015/kd-visits-dc</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-10-2015/kd-visits-dc</guid>
        
        
        <category>durant</category>
        
        <category>oped</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Game Recap: Thunder vs. Suns</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;okc-124---pho-103&quot;&gt;OKC 124 - PHO 103&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder ended the first (and hopefully only) losing streak of the season. It was another Sunset Sunday with the Thunder wearing the new Sunday alternates. Oklahoma City put together a full game for the first time this season, winning three quarters and tying one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder came out blazing in the first quarter pushing the lead to 15 points before the second unit allowed the lead to slip. The starters combined for 19 points on 9-of-16 shooting while the second unit went just 3-of-9 for 8 points. Kevin Durant got hot immediately shooting 3-of-4 and scoring 8 in the quarter while Russell Westbrook went 3-of-6 for 6 points and added 6 assists as well. Eric Bledsoe had a huge quarter for the Suns making 6-of-7 from the floor and scoring 15 in the first frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second quarter saw the return of the first unit and a win for the quarter – outscoring Phoenix 31-25. Dion Waiters got things turned around shooting a perfect 3-of-3 from the field, and 4-of-4 from the charity stripe to score 10 in the quarter. The Thunder went into halftime leading 60-54.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second half was the big difference for the Thunder. They extended the lead to double digits again in the third quarter. The starters played significant minutes coming out of halftime, with the exception of Steven Adams who logged only 4:21 in the third with Enes Kanter relieving him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final quarter saw the Thunder push the lead to the eventual blowout that the game became. The bench was seen as a strength for the Thunder coming in to the season but it has been disappointing compared to the hype it received as possibly being the deepest team assembled in Oklahoma City. The second unit redeemed itself in the fourth quarter though. In the final quarter the reserves combined to go 8-of-11 for 20 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In just six minutes, Kevin Durant had a perfect quarter going 5-of-5 from the field (including a made three) for 11 points in just 6:34. Kanter tied Durant for leading scorer of the quarter shooting an efficient 5-of-5 and converting his only free throw after an a foul and made basket. Dion Waiters, not to be left out, joined the perfect quarter club and finished the quarter with 5 points on 2-of-2 shooting, including a basket from behind the arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Durant lead all scorers with a quiet 32 points on 12-of-19 shooting. He completed the double-double by pulling down 11 boards as well. Russell Westbrook joined Kevin Durant in the double-double club scoring 21 points on 9-of-20 shooting and dishing out 13 assists. It was his fourth game in a row with a double-double and his fifth overall on the season. Enes Kanter and Dion Waiters joined in the scoring fun from the bench. Kanter finished with 21 points while shooting 90 percent from the floor (9/10) and converting all 3 of his free throw attempts. He pulled down 7 rebounds too. Waiters pitched in 19 points on an efficient 6-of-9 shooting and forced 3 turnovers, reaching into the cookie jar for 3 steals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thunder fans continue to be baffled by Anthony Morrow’s absence from the rotation. He logged his first DNP-Coach’s Decision of the season, joining Nick Collison as the only players to leave their warmups on all game. Coach Billy Donovan attributed it to the matchups, though Morrow has not seen significant minutes the last 4 games. He failed to score in all 4 games in very playing time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder take on the Washington Wizards in a homecoming game for Kevin Durant on Tuesday, November 10th. The game will be carried by NBATV and Fox Sports Oklahoma with tipoff occurring at 6 pm Central Standard Time. Kevin Durant recently stated that the Washington fans openly attempting to court him before his looming free agency was “disrespectful” to the team they currently have. It should prove to be an interesting game. It could also be Billy Donovan’s first game against Bradley Beal who played for Donovan at Florida before leaving for the NBA. Beal is listed as questionable for the game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 21:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/11-09-2015/game-recap-suns1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/11-09-2015/game-recap-suns1</guid>
        
        
        <category>phx</category>
        
        <category>recap</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
