<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thunder Op-Ed</title>
    <description>Welcome to Thunder Op-Ed! Come back often or follow us on twitter  for content, thoughts, and ramblings on your Oklahoma City Thunder. This site is independent of the OKC Thunder organization and all views expressed are that of the author.
</description>
    <link>http://thunderoped.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thunderoped.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 01:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 01:50:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cameron Payne Season Preview</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As with most rookies drafted onto a team fighting for a championship, the story of Cameron Payne his rookie season will be how and if he carves out a role. No one is taking Russell Westbrook’s spot and D.J. Augustin defines ‘solid’ as a backup floor general. If Payne hopes to find minutes for himself he’ll need to shake off the rookie jitters and show what he brings that Augustin can’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He are a few things that we are keeping an eye on with Payne this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calm--control&quot;&gt;Calm / Control&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-24/payne1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Jim Brown – USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rookies make mistakes. Rookie point guard mistakes stand out. When the ball is in your hands and you dribble it off your foot, or you pass behind yourself on a fast break to no one in particular, people notice. Moving past these moments and learning from them will be crucial to Payne’s place on the roster this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has the skills and practice operating with all the eyes on him from his time at Murray State, but both the metaphorical and literal bright lights and sounds of the NBA add their own distractions. Payne is fighting for a roster spot with a player in D.J. Augustin who has stuck in the league because he knows what he brings. He’s not long and athletic. He is however, a solid shooter and passer. He fits in and does his job without standing out. Payne is athletic and a much more exciting player, but his rookie season will be best served mimicking the intangibles of Augustin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calm and collected play is a necessary element for a backup point guard, especially one that would be taking the floor with Enes Kanter and Dion Waiters. There’s already enough offensive flash to go around. Payne’s personality is anything but subtle, but for him to grab hold of a spot in this rotation he’ll need to make sure he isn’t shaken when staring down the Chris Pauls of the league.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;minutes&quot;&gt;Minutes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-24/payne2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Sue Ogrocki - Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first look at Payne had a lot of people, myself included, locking him in to play rotation minutes by at least the All-Star break. Even if the excitement reasonably tapered off as some rookie mistakes set in, there’s still ways he could receive regular minutes this season. Two point guard lineups were fairly common under Scott Brooks, and having three point guards all receiving minutes was the norm in past seasons with Westbrook, Reggie Jackson, and Derrick Fisher on the roster. If Billy Donovan sees advantages to those lineups too it could be one way Payne sees minutes without leapfrogging Augustin’s spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing standing in Payne’s way, however, is that Mitch McGary may deserve the minutes more. He can pass, attack, rebound, and has proven he can spark this team back to life. Depending on Collison’s play and how rotations work themselves out McGary may be the better bet to crack a rotation and receive currently invisible minutes that Payne is hoping to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Payne will receive minutes in garbage time. If he can make the scrubs pay like Jeremy Lamb never could it could help his case. Westbrook also may sit during some back-to-backs against the bottom of the East (or the Lakers), and this frees up minutes for Payne. Barring injuries, these games may be the best chance Payne has to prove himself in an actual game situation when the points really matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot is up in the air, and the most surefire way to crack the rotation is to take Augustin’s spot. That, however, will require Payne to bring something special…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-he-bring&quot;&gt;What Does He Bring?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-24/payne3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Charles Rex Arbogast - Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Blue/White Scrimmage, Cameron Payne came out guns blazing. He was knocking down his 3-pointers and floaters, manipulating his defender where he wanted him, and hitting his man for wide open shots. Then the preseason moved out of the highschool gym and into the NBA arena and Payne came down to Earth. No one forgot the explosive edge he brought, however, and he’s still a pass-first point guard that isn’t just looking to get his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Payne to get rotation minutes he’ll have to do more than show maturity and calm beyond his years and experience. They already have that player in Augustin. He’ll also have to bring something beyond consistent shooting, because Augustin isn’t an unknown their either. Payne is going to have to bring something special that really opens up other facets of Coach Billy Donovan’s offense. If he can collapse defenses attacking the paint, beat his man off the dribble, move well off the ball, and be a reliable pest on defense then Payne has a rotation spot. It may be just one or two of these points, but he’ll need to figure out where his strengths lie and how to use them effectively while also matching Augustin’s strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-24/payne4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Brad Penner - USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder aren’t going to leave anything to chance, because they both can’t afford and don’t have to with the proven players on this roster. Cameron Payne has the talent to take the backup spot for his own. The only question is whether he can put it all in place do to so in this pressure cooker season.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/10-24-2015/payne-preview</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/10-24-2015/payne-preview</guid>
        
        
        <category>payne</category>
        
        <category>preseason</category>
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>D.J. Augustin Season Preview</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;D.J. Augustin, an underrated part of the Reggie Jackson trade last season, will look to continue his success as a backup point guard in the 2015-16 season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augustin played just 28 games with the Thunder last season, and though he didn’t particularly shine, he brought smart and solid play to the Thunder’s second unit. In 24 minutes per game, he averaged 7.3 points and 3.1 assists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He are a few things that we are looking for with Augustin this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;minutes&quot;&gt;Minutes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-23/Augustin 1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Sue Ogrocki – The Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augustin will begin the season as the Thunder’s backup point guard, but unlike last season, he may end up with some competition for that role. Cameron Payne, the Thunder’s first round draft pick out of Murray State, is a highly regarded rookie who will no doubt be looking to climb the depth chart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Payne actually outplayed Augustin for the most part in preseason, and though that won’t necessarily be characteristic of the season, it’s something to look out for. The Thunder certainly drafted Payne with the future in mind, but who knows if that future will come sooner than expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another scenario is Payne and Augustin sharing time, but considering they’ll be backing up Russell Westbrook, there won’t be a lot of minutes to go around. It’ll be interesting to see who holds the backup job by the end of the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assists&quot;&gt;Assists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-23/Augustin 2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Sue Ogrocki – The Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augustin has never been an assist machine by any means, but in his time with Oklahoma City last season he just averaged 3.1 assists per game, down almost two from the 4.9 he was averaging in Detroit in about the same amount of minutes played.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augustin will likely see most his minutes with guys like Dion Waiters, Anthony Morrow and Enes Kanter, and this should give him plenty of opportunities to find open shots for his teammates. He can be a big part of a second unit that may be a defensive nightmare, but that should be able to score with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for Augustin to do some more distributing and up his assist numbers this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shooting&quot;&gt;Shooting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-23/Augustin 3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Soobum Im - USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augustin is a career 40 percent shooter, but shot just 37 percent with the Thunder last season. This includes about 35 percent from three, down from his career percentage of 37.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augustin is not anywhere near the top of the list when it comes to Thunder scoring options, but he’s got to be able to score when open, and it would be excellent to see him hover around 40 percent from three, a number he’s eclipsed a few times in his career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augustin shot about 27 percent in preseason, and only made one 3-pointer in 10 attempts. Shooting like this may find him in a position with less minutes, so it will be interesting to see how he can improve as the regular season opens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-23/Augustin 4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Sue Ogrocki – The Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augustin is a smart player who should continue to succeed as a backup point guard, and as long as he is able to keep his place on the depth chart, he should provide some positive contributions for the Thunder this season.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/10-23-2015/augustin-preview</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/10-23-2015/augustin-preview</guid>
        
        
        <category>augustin</category>
        
        <category>preseason</category>
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anthony Morrow Season Preview</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In his second season in Oklahoma City, 3-point sharpshooter Anthony Morrow will look to continue the success he saw in his first year as a member of the Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morrow, arguably one of Sam Presti’s best free agent signings to date, led the Thunder in 3-pointers (141) and 3-point percentage (43 percent) last season. He averaged 10.7 points in 24.4 minutes per game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morrow has really flourished in his role with the Thunder so far, and there’s no reason to think he won’t continue his success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some things we’re looking for with Morrow this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;minutes&quot;&gt;Minutes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-22/Morrow 1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Chris Humphreys-USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given Morrow’s success last year, he should still see plenty of minutes this season, but there may be less minutes to go around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A healthy Thunder will have three shooting guards, Morrow, Dion Waiters and Andre Roberson, who will likely see regular minutes. The Thunder will also probably feature a two point guard set from time to time, with Russell Westbrook and D.J. Augustin, and perhaps Cameron Payne. Kyle Singler is likely to get some minutes too, though these will most likely come from backing up Kevin Durant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see how new head coach Billy Donovan mixes and matches lineups, but hopefully the Thunder’s depth won’t keep Morrow from succeeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;big-games&quot;&gt;Big Games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-22/Morrow 2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Mark D. Smith – USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morrow’s always most likely to hover around 10 or 12 points per game, but last season he showed that he’s capable of getting hot and going off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morrow eclipsed 20 points six times last season, including a season high of 32 in a loss against Dallas. This isn’t the norm, but it should happen again considering the amount of open looks he should get with the Thunder’s deep offensive repertoire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morrow is always a fun player to watch, but when he gets on a roll he is virtually unstoppable. While this won’t happen every game, look for him to have some really strong performances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;energy&quot;&gt;Energy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-22/Morrow 3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Mark L. Baer - USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morrow is one of the most energetic players in the NBA, and he is always very excited when he succeeds or sees his teammates succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy isn’t something that shows up in the box score, but it contributes a lot to a team’s morale, and is great for sparking rallies. When watching Morrow, whether he’s on the court or on the bench, it’s easy to see that he loves the game and really wants his teammates to succeed. He wants to win, and he’s not afraid to show it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s Thunder squad should be really fun to watch, and there’s no doubt that Morrow and his energy will contribute to the entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-22/Morrow 4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Sue Ogrocki – The Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morrow had a lot of success in his first season with OKC, and this year we are hoping to see much of the same from the 3-point sniper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/10-22-2015/morrow-preview</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/10-22-2015/morrow-preview</guid>
        
        
        <category>morrow</category>
        
        <category>preseason</category>
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Josh Huestis Season Preview</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-21/huestis.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Oklahoma City Blue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huestis was a first round draft pick (29th Overall) in the 2014 NBA draft. Instead of immediately signing with the Thunder he instead played for a year in the NBA D-League with the Oklahoma City affiliate – The Blue. If he accomplishes nothing else in his time in the NBA he will be a historical tidbit known as the first ever “domestic draft-and-stash.” In his one season in the D-League Huestis had a solid season. Huestis played in 44 games, starting in 43, and averaged 10.3 PPG, 4.6 RPG, 1.1 APG, and 1.6 BPG in just over 33 minutes per game. Huestis also finished his college career as the leading shot blocker in Stanford basketball history. A lot has been made of his intelligence, but we have yet to see how it converts to court production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things to watch over the course of the season:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;number-of-games&quot;&gt;Number of Games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect that Huestis will move fluidly back and forth across Reno Avenue. He will continue to see his fair share of D-League games, while also making an attempt to crack an absolutely stacked OKC roster. Huestis and his management view him as a small forward rather than a power forward or stretch 4 like he played at Stanford. Turns out being a small forward on the same team as Kevin Durant makes finding minutes difficult. The most accurate comparison for Huestis in terms of games played might be Jeremy Lamb and Perry Jones. Early in their stints in OKC they moved up and down between the NBA and D-League. Huestis will do the same this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;role&quot;&gt;Role&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project. Huestis has talent. Anyone who has watched the Thunder over their OKC tenure knows that they will attempt to make the most out of any first round draft pick. Huestis will get his opportunity to stay with the organization, but finding actual minutes will be difficult. He will be an energy guy that can play multiple positions during walk-throughs and practices. He provides great length and will do whatever is asked of him, which in itself can disrupt opponents. His year in the D-League may have been his best shot to prove himself in the NBA, considering how thin the OKC bench got during last seasons injury plague. There’s a very good chance he only sees the floor of Chesapeake Energy Arena during massive blowout games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;domestic-draft-and-stash-effects&quot;&gt;Domestic Draft and Stash Effects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder drafted Huestis out of Stanford in the first round of the 2014 NBA Draft. First round draft picks historically receive guaranteed contracts. Huestis, however, did not sign the contract. Instead he spent one year in the D-League, which allowed Oklahoma City to avoid a luxury tax situation and also allowed one more open roster spot. Huestis did this on the promise of Oklahoma City signing him to his deal after one year. This summer, Oklahoma City made good on the arrangement and signed Huestis to a 4-year rookie-scale deal. This deal actually ended up being worth more money than if he had signed immediately after the draft. In terms of Oklahoma City’s tax situation, the domestic draft-and-stash worked great. Huestis was not on the roster and so his salary did not count against the cap limit. The Thunder are in a predicament this season however, as signing Huestis pushed the Thunder to the NBA maximum 15 players on the roster. Typically Sam Presti has preferred to keep an open roster spot for flexibility, but that is not the case this season so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to a successful rookie season, Mr. Huestis!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 19:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/10-21-2015/huestis-preview</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/10-21-2015/huestis-preview</guid>
        
        
        <category>huestis</category>
        
        <category>preseason</category>
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Steve Novak Season Preview</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few seasons ago, when Durant and the Thunder were working their way to their first Finals appearance, Steve Novak was in the Big Apple leading the league with a .472 3-point shooting percentage and throwing the Discount Double Check. Now he’s closer to the end of a stacked bench with resident sniper, Anthony Morrow, ahead of him on the depth chart. We know what Novak can bring on the court and what he cant, but there might be other ways Novak can help this team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things to look for from Novak this season:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;readiness&quot;&gt;Readiness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-20/1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Russ Isabella - USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shooting is as much rhythm as anything, and sitting on a bench for the majority of a game before being asked to come in and hit big shots is a trying task for anyone. This may just be the role Coach Donovan asks Novak to play this season, and as we saw the other night against Denver this could end up with a few airballs and bricks if Novak isn’t completely dialed in. Playing time will be hard to come by on this team, so how ready will Novak be when his number is called?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mentorship&quot;&gt;Mentorship&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-20/2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Twitter - @stevenovak16&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steven Novak as been around the league a few times. He helped Kanter with his transition to OKC as they both departed Salt Lake City together at the trade deadline last season. He also has a very honed skill set that this Thunder team has struggled with in the pre-season: 3-point shooting. Sam Presti has a history of bringing in players that can act as mentors to the team’s younger players. Derrick Fisher, Kendrick Perkins, and Royal Ivey all spend multiple seasons on the team and left lasting impressions that have been invaluable. It’s very possible Presti sees this potential in Novak as well. He has the ability to connect with younger players as demonstrated with Enes Kanter. It also doesn’t hurt to have him around to try and smooth the waters with the Thunder’s new post-up luxury piece, who has a history of becoming disgruntled with his employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;extra-shooter-vs-trade-piece&quot;&gt;Extra Shooter vs. Trade Piece&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-20/3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Russ Isabella - USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam Presti likes roster flexibility. He’s put together an extremely balanced squad, but one thing is noticeably different going into this season: There’s no empty roster spot. In years past the Thunder have entered the season with a 14 man roster, usually filling it near the end of the season plugging a gap as the teams gets ready for a deep playoff run. Novak would be the 15th man on the roster, and many expected him to be traded by this point. No one knows what Presti is planning, but it may not necessarily be to use Novak as a trade piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, 3-point shooting is a weakness on this team outside of a few players, namely Morrow, Durant, and Ibaka. Having the ability to spread the floor and keep the defense honest with 4 or 5 shooters out on the court is the new hot thing in the NBA. Back in the 2012 Finals, Miami used this tactic to run the Thunder into the ground. Mike Miller and Shane Battier were as much to blame as Lebron in many ways, and it’s not likely Thunder brass forgot this. Having a shooter as accomplished as Novak as the 15th man on the roster could be exactly what Presti wants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-20/4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Ron Antonelli - New York Daily News&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Novak is a journeyman closer to the end of his playing career than not, but he still has things to offer. What that may end up being is up in the air as much as it is with anyone on the roster. This preseason, however, he showed what kind of shooter he still is, and as long as that remains a weakness on this team it means there could very well be a spot on the Thunder for Steve Novak to make a difference. He most likely won’t be a steady part of the rotation, but look for him to be used in spots when shots aren’t falling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/10-20-2015/novak-preview</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/10-20-2015/novak-preview</guid>
        
        
        <category>novak</category>
        
        <category>preseason</category>
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Andre Roberson Season Preview</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Andre Roberson just finished his second season for the Oklahoma City Thunder. He appeared in only 67 games (starting 65) due to injury. His first season as a starter in the NBA went according to plan, sliding into the starting five after Thabo Sefolosha left for the Atlanta Hawks. He made improvements in many aspects of his game during the jump to his second year. He increased his points per game and three point shooting percentage while he saw a slight dip in field goal percentage that comes from taking more shots and playing more minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things we would like to see from Roberson:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;defense&quot;&gt;Defense&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-19/roberson2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Mark D. Smith – USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no question why Roberson is in the starting line up. It is his defense. He brings length and athleticism to the defensive end of the court. The 6’7” shooting guard has a 6’11” wingspan that he often uses to disrupt opposing offensive schemes. He averaged nearly one steal every game last season in just under 20 minutes per game. Roberson knows what his role on the team is: defensive stopper. It is a role that he seems perfectly content with occupying. He puts in far more effort on that end of the floor and looks more comfortable guarding the ball rather than holding it. He will continue to play that role and he will do it well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;slashing--finishing&quot;&gt;Slashing / Finishing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-19/roberson3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;NBC Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roberson has shown regularly that he has the ability to finish around the rim. He does not regularly influence on the offensive end of the court, but he does, however, have the ability to slash to the basket when the opportunity presents itself. Roberson will not create often for himself, but he excels when the ball is passed around the perimeter and opposing defenders get lost or are constantly shifting. It creates lanes and openings for him to get into the paint. Motion and spacing is a key part of Coach Donovan’s new offense, which could pay dividends for Roberson this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;point-shooting&quot;&gt;3-Point Shooting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-19/roberson4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Gary A. Vasquez – USA Today Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the biggest area of improvement that we need to see from Roberson. Last season he shot only 24.7% from beyond the arc. In order for Roberson to fulfill his potential and really help this team out then he needs to increase that percentage. Nobody is expecting Roberson to shoot 40% from deep and score double digit points every night, but if he could raise the three point shooting percentage to just 30% or slightly higher then he will help the team even more than he already does. Roberson has shown he has the ability, but comfindence may be the key to his improvement. His 3-point shot dropped over 30 percentage points when simply comparing away versus home games, where he only made one 3-pointer all season. If he improves this will open the court up more for other players as well as himself. When defenders are forced to cover the 3-point line Roberson will be able to attack the paint and show off his finishing ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-19/roberson1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Andre Roberson - Twitter (@FlyDre21)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andre Roberson is a perfect fit for this roster, particularly considering the rest of the options at shooting guard. With Anthony Morrow and Dion Waiters playing behind Roberson there is a lot of offense. Roberson counters their skillset with a defensive centered one. He will continue to be an important part of the OKC Thunder. In his third year in the NBA he will continue to grow and improve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/10-19-2015/roberson-preview</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/10-19-2015/roberson-preview</guid>
        
        
        <category>roberson</category>
        
        <category>preseason</category>
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eyeball Test: Nuggets @ Thunder</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;den-98---okc-111&quot;&gt;DEN 98 - OKC 111&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No TV broadcast, but a complimentary online stream? Sounds good to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The beginning of the game showed great movement and more comfort from the starters. Lots of Adams (even though he was still struggling to catch Westbrook passes at the beginning of the game), including a beautiful find of a cutting Westbrook.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Durant is back boys and girls. He struggled at the beginning of the Mavericks game last Tuesday, but he was in rhythm and looked very comfortable to start tonight: cutting, passing, crossing over defenders, nailing a straight-away three pointer, and initiating contact to get to the line.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Against the Mavs the Thunder looked like they were thinking about their movements. Those movements appeared much more natural tonight, which bodes well for early season success as they continue to learn Donovan’s system.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preseason prediction: Emmanuel Mudiay wins Rookie of the Year (and the Lakers punch themselves in the face).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preseason prediction #2: Ibaka’s offensive numbers increase. He hit multiple floaters within just a few feet of the basket in the first quarter, catching the ball several feet closer than the 18-19 foot sweet spot he’s perfected over the years.  Ibaka’s offense has never been dependent on plays drawn up for him, instead relying on hitting his spots. If his ‘spots’ are closer to the basket under Donovan that’s good for Ibaka and the Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kanter hustle defense caused a travel? Good sign. He also had 6 fouls, which I’ll take as another good sign based on defensive effort alone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kanter wants his. If he’s within 20 feet the ball stops with him. He’s very talented, and when he has the ball it’s usually very close to the basket which is more often than not a big plus. It’s something to watch, however, because even if he doesn’t care that he’s the sixth or seventh man I wouldn’t call him selfless.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s a bad snap judgement to make without a larger sample size, or any regular season action, but I wouldn’t have many (any?) reservations to Presti signing Waiters to an extension before the Nov. 2nd deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lots of turnovers, but Westbrook threw a decent number of cross court prayers over multiple defenders that didn’t go his way. He always has and always will take chances, but I have a feeling the nature of regular season games actually counting will reduce some of these turnovers. That’s the hope at least.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Coach Billy Donovan said realistic rotations would start to make an appearance the final two preseason games. Compared to the bulk substitutions we’ve seen until this point, it was interesting to see who was first to replace who. Kyle Singler came in for Roberson after he picked up two fouls, and later Waiters was brought in to replace Durant. Despite the guard/forward position switch, with Singler at the 2 and Waiters at the 3, based on their styles of play these substitutions make a lot of sense. Singler seems a much closer Roberson replacement, and Waiters helps spell some of the scoring and playmaking drop-off when Durant goes to the bench.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Westbrook is guarding Danilo Gallinari and the Italian goes flying, did Gallinari just fall down or did Westbrook simply throw him aside? Either is totally plausible.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Three point shooting remains a struggle. Even the team’s resident shooters struggled mightily. Morrow couldn’t find his range and Novak even air-balled a three. Waiter’s however? two of four from deep.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Watching this game on the Thunder’s online stream means I had no idea the score. I would have never guessed the game was as close as it was in the third quarter, but the Nuggets were allowed quite a few threes. Old habits die hard.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mudiay is good. Durant is better. He’s definitely back and that is very, very good to see. The Westbrook triple-double machine we became acquainted with last season also continues to be on display. The heads of the hydra now know their individual potentials, and working together doesn’t seem to be reducing that in any way. This season is going to be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Injuries: Kanter is back and looked good. McGary has a concussion, and Adams got knocked out with an eye injury after a powerful first half. Hopefully the Thunder’s deep big man rotation can get healthy soon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;eyeball-test&quot;&gt;Eyeball Test?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comfortable.&lt;/strong&gt; Where they go, and how they fit is sinking in. Defense can always use work, but Durant looks better and better as the Thunder move closer to their season tipoff hosting the Spurs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/10-18-2015/den-okc-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/10-18-2015/den-okc-notes</guid>
        
        
        <category>den</category>
        
        <category>preseason</category>
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dion Waiters Season Preview</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-17/Waiters 1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Kelley L. Cox- USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dion Waiters is coming off his worst season yet in the NBA, but he’ll look to turn it around in his first full season with the Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The former fourth overall draft pick, who joined the Thunder last season in a trade with the Cleveland Cavaliers, averaged 12.7 points, 2.9 rebounds and 1.9 assists per game, but shot only 39 percent from the field with the Thunder. He showed some flashes of being a great addition to the Thunder, but has yet to consistently contribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some things to look for in Dion’s game this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finishing&quot;&gt;Finishing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-17/Waiters 2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Sue Ogrocki – The Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone that has watched Waiters play can see that he has a great ability to get to the rim. There’s just one thing missing from this skill: he doesn’t finish well. Waiters shot just 48 percent on lay ups last year, and while that percentage would be fantastic for an overall field goal percentage, it is not very good for such close range shots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For comparison, Russell Westbrook’s percentage on lay ups was 54, and a few other young shooting guards, Bradley Beal and Klay Thompson, shot 57 and 64 percent, respectively. There’s no question that Westbrook, Beal and Thompson are better players than Waiters overall, but there’s no reason that he shouldn’t be able to shoot a higher percentage on these close range shots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Waiters can improve in this area, he will become a lot more dangerous on the offensive side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-throws&quot;&gt;Free Throws&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-17/Waiters 3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Mark D. Smith – USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waiters has never been an excellent free throw shooter, averaging just 70 percent from the line in his career, but his 62 percent with the Thunder last season was the worst of his career. A percentage like that is really unacceptable for a shooting guard, and this is an area where Waiters must improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He only averaged 2.4 free throw attempts per game with the Thunder, but the low frequency of attempts doesn’t excuse the percentage. Perhaps the strangest thing about his shooting woes from the line with OKC was that he was shooting 78 percent with Cleveland before his trade to the Thunder, which is a much more acceptable number. This shows that he’s capable of improving in this area, so hopefully he worked on this in the offseason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who have watched the preseason games can see that he is starting to shoot his free throws lined up to the right of the basket, which is abnormal, but it shows that he’s making an effort to improve. He’s shot just 66 percent from the line so far in the preseason, but given his interest in improving and his higher career percentage, Thunder fans can be optimistic that he will improve his free throw shooting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;passing&quot;&gt;Passing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-17/Waiters 4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Derick E. Hingle – USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waiters has never averaged more than three assists per game, and he averaged just 1.9 with the Thunder last year. However, watching him play shows that he actually is a very skilled passer, though not always willing. Hopefully he will start to showcase his distributing abilities more this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waiters is likely going to be the Thunder’s sixth man, or may share this role with Enes Kanter, but either way he should have the ball in his hands a lot. For this reason, he should look to feed second unit guys like Kanter, Anthony Morrow and D.J. Augustin. With so many offensive weapons on this year’s Thunder squad, Waiters should easily be able to up his assist numbers, that is if he shows more of a willingness to share the basketball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder were near the bottom in team assists per game last year, and this should definitely improve this season. There’s no reason that Waiters can’t be a part of this improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-17/Waiters 5.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Sue Ogrocki – The Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though Waiters often struggled last year in OKC, Thunder fans should look forward to some potential improvements. He seems happy as a member of this team, and the team is happy to have him. Here’s hoping that being in a good situation will allow him to improve and exceed expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/10-17-2015/waiters-preview</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/10-17-2015/waiters-preview</guid>
        
        
        <category>waiters</category>
        
        <category>preseason</category>
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Steven Adams Season Preview</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-16/0.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Mark D. Smith - USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the 2012-13 season there were no mysteries about what type of player the Thunder were going to draft. They had the 12th pick and they needed a big man. OKC fans were in the midst of screaming for Perkins’ head, and no matter whether Presti listened or not (he didn’t) there was no hiding the inevitable: Perkins was overpriced and didn’t have any knees left. The Thunder needed a center for the future who could learn from Perk before he left town and who could dole out the same type of punishments. Enter Adams and his bone-crushing screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was two seasons ago, and support for Adams has grown in similar fasion to his hair and personality. Energy (diving for loose balls and sprinting back on defense) and strength (he isn’t getting moved by anyone on defense) will never be in short supply for Steven Adams. The raw athleticism and potential have always been there, but his game is continuing to expand. I’ve ignored defense for this post, because we already know the reason Billy Donovan appears to favor Adams in his starting lineup this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things to look for with Adams this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;offense&quot;&gt;Offense&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-16/3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Darren Abate – Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The potential has always been there for Adams. In only his fifth outing for the Thunder during his rookie season he dropped 17 points and 10 rebounds on Detroit when facing another up and coming inside force, Andre Drummond. He also added 3 blocks, a steal, and 3 assists while shooting 70 percent. Adams is strong, and his size and rugby background have set him up perfectly for battling around the basket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunder don’t expect, or need, Adams to put up those type of numbers on anything resembling a regular basis. His inside presence on the offensive end, however, results in lots of offensive rebounds, and any extra possesions in a lineup with the three-headed offensive snake of Durant-Westbrook-Ibaka is dangerous against any opponent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adams isn’t simply restricted to offensive rebounds though. He has been improving on a hook shot that has looked deadly at times. It will be interesting to see how it has improved in the offseason and how Coach Donovan may or may not utilize it. Additionaly, setting screens was a reason I was high on Adams coming out of Pitt in his single college season. Last year Adams would open up a direct path down the lane for Westbrook as he screened multiple defenders out of the way. With Durant injected back into the lineup, and with Donovan’s spacing offense, it will be intriging to see what using Adams as a moving wall can do for the Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hands&quot;&gt;Hands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-16/2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;David Zalubowski – Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big men in the NBA are often referred to by their hands. How do they catch passes, and how is their touch around the basket? Kendrick Perkins had ‘bricks’ for hands. Enes Kanter has ‘soft’ hands. Where does Adams fall? Somewhere in between probably. Considering his skillset and those of Westbrook and Durant, having ‘soft’ hands will be important as Adams continues to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past Adams has talked about practicing receiving rifle passes at his head to better prepare for working alongside Westbrook. Against the Mavs he caught one beautifully as Westbrook dumped it down to him under the basket, and then a few plays later it bounced off his hands out of bounds. Improving on consistency here could be a big plus for the Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adams has a scar running down the back of the hand he broke last season; a reminder of the glove he wore for a good chunk of games and the halted progress in his post catches and especially his free throw shooting (despite making the lefty, one-hander seconds after braking his hand). In the preseason, Adams’ free throw shooting mechanics look improved, and he has mentioned free throw shooting as an area he worked on in the offseason. It’ll be interesting to see what difference it makes once there’s a larger sample size to go off of. Adams could be a major asset at the end of games defensively if he isn’t a liability with Hack-A-Kiwi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;opponent-aggravation&quot;&gt;Opponent Aggravation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-16/1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Mark D. Smith – USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adams has been the model pupil when it comes to ‘tricks of the trade.’ Big man coach Mark Bryant hasn’t been shy giving Adams tips on hooking arms, grabbing, and shoving opposing big men when battling down low without alerting the refs. By combining these talents with the stoic, calm demeanor he maintains throughout games he has found another useful skill: Aggravating his opponents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His rookie season he tallied multiple opponent ejections for his efforts, but last season players adjusted enough to keep their rage in check. Less punches were thrown at Adams (see Zach Randolph) but frustrations still ran high, and in the game of basketball frustration easily turns into uncessesary fouls and easy mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If nothing else, it’s an amusing piece of Adams’ game and personality to follow, but there’s a reason guys in the NBA trash talk. Adams may have perfected it without needing to open his mouth. What to watch for is when the refs will catch on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-6/collison-adams.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Steven Adams – Instagram&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know what Adams brings defensively. There’s only optimism in his development, and he’s a hard worker with offensive potential as well. Include his budding friendship with Nick Collison, chronicled &lt;a href=&quot;/2015-10-10-steven-adams-quotes/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and there’s a chance that his overall cerebral approach to the game builds as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/10-16-2015/adams-preview</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/10-16-2015/adams-preview</guid>
        
        
        <category>adams</category>
        
        <category>preseason</category>
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Enes Kanter Season Preview</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-15/1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Sue Ogrocki - Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enes Kanter is coming off of his best season yet in the NBA, one that was split between the Utah Jazz and the Thunder. Kanter became a member of the Thunder after Sam Presti pulled the trigger on a blockbuster deal that also landed Oklahoma City D.J. Augustin, Kyle Singler and Steve Novak. He jumped right into his new role in OKC, and now is here to stay after signing a monster 4-year contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 26 games with the Thunder, his minutes went up, as did his production. In 31 minutes per game, up four from his time with the Jazz, he averaged 18.7 points on 57 percent shooting and 11 rebounds. Perhaps most impressive was that he averaged five offensive rebounds per game. Looking at numbers like these, there isn’t much room to question Kanter’s worth for the Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things to look for with Kanter this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;post-scoring&quot;&gt;Post scoring&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-15/2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Mark D. Smith – USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanter brings the Thunder something its never truly had on a consistent basis, and that is low post scoring. Serge Ibaka has never developed much in that area, and having bigs like Steven Adams and Kendrick Perkins has never helped fill that void either. This makes Kanter a crucial part of what should prove to be an explosive Thunder offense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we should expect to see some midrange game and perhaps a few three pointers here and there, Kanter should really be earning his money in the paint. Last year he shot 83, 53 and 66 percent on dunks, hook shots and layups respectively. These shots are all products of working hard in the post, and the efficiency he’s shown in that area shows his offensive strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great thing about Kanter’s post scoring is that it takes some of the offensive pressure of the Thunder’s big three of Kevin Durant, Russell Westbrook and Ibaka, and it should also help open up shots for guys like Dion Waiters, Anthony Morrow and D.J. Augustin. Kanter’s success in the post should help the Thunder reach its full potential offensively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rebounding&quot;&gt;Rebounding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-15/3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Mark J. Terrill – Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanter is an excellent rebounder on both sides of the floor, and his 11 rpg with the Thunder shows that. He also had a total rebounding percentage of 19 with the Thunder, which would have put him amongst the league leaders were it for the whole season. While his time with the Thunder carries a limited sample size so far, there’s no reason to believe he can’t keep up numbers like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanter’s defensive rebounding is important because it can help the Thunder reduce second chance opportunities on defense, and it gives the Thunder some back up on the glass for when Ibaka is focusing on protecting the rim. It also allows Kanter to contribute on the defensive side of the court, an area where he struggles overall (more on that later). His offensive rebounding is extremely important as well, as it will give a Thunder offense with so many scoring options extra chances, something that should allow the team to dominate games offensively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanter is one of the better rebounders the Thunder has had, so look for him to continue his success crashing the boards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;defense&quot;&gt;Defense&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-15/4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Mark D. Smith – USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should be Thunder fans’ biggest concern for the young center. Defense is really the only noticeable hole in Kanter’s game. In fact, with Kanter on the court for OKC last year, the opponent’s offensive rating was 111.7, and with him off it was 103.9. This shows that his defensive capabilities have been severely lacking up to this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to say what the primary cause of this, but after watching him play, it seems like a mix of lack of effort and limited basketball IQ on the defensive side. He is a young guy, entering just his fifth year in the NBA, and is now on a great team with an exciting new coach, so for now Thunder fans should remain optimistic that he can improve on the defensive side. His offense and rebounding skills are there and still improving, and hopefully his defense will soon follow suit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Kanter can improve defensively, there’s really nothing keeping him from being one of the best centers in the league. That’s a big if, but only time will tell what improvements he is able to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/2015-10-15/5.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px;display:block;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tagline&quot;&gt;Russ Isabella – USA TODAY Sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanter should continue his overall success with the Thunder this year, and is an exciting part of an offense that features two things it’s never really had on a consistent basis: post scoring and three point shooting depth. Whether he starts or comes off the bench, look for him to be a big part of the Thunder’s success this season.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thunderoped.com/10-15-2015/kanter-preview</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thunderoped.com/10-15-2015/kanter-preview</guid>
        
        
        <category>mcgary</category>
        
        <category>preseason</category>
        
        <category>preview</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
